[birds chirping]
[นกร้อง]
[waves splashing]
[คลิ่น]
[rock 'n' roll music playing]
[ดนตรึร็อกจ์งหวะเร็ว]
[music increases in tempo]
[จ์งหวะดนตรึเร็วขี้น]
♪ Before ♪
อืก่ อนวีนนี๊นมิ
♪ You and I were good friends ♪
มิสองเราผูกพันคสํายเพี่อนอื
♪ You once told me ♪
มิเธอเคยเตือนมิ
♪ That we should stay friends ♪
มิใหัคนดื่งเพี่อนรึกไวัมิ
♪ But in my mind ♪
อืเเตํในใจมิ
♪ I always hoped that We would be more than friends ♪
มิคอยหวีงโหัเราผุกพันก๊นมากกวําเพี่อนดืมิ
♪ So I gave you all my heart ♪
มิจีงใหั เธ อทั้งใจมิ
♪ Stop being nice if you don't love me ♪
มิไม่รึกก็อย่าทําเหึนใจมิ
♪ If you want to leave me ♪
อืถัาเลีอกจะไปอื
♪ Just tell me the truth ♪
มิเเค่บอกความ จริง เท่านี๊นมิ
♪ Stop hurting me By saying I'm too good ♪
มิอย่ามาฆ่าก๊นตัวยคําวําดืเกึนไปมิ
[engine accelerating]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[horn honking]
[บีบ เเต ร]
New kid?
เต็กใหม่เหรอ
Want to come with me?
ไปตํวยก๊นเปล่า
[exhilarating music playing]
[ดนตรึจีงหวะเร็ว]
[thunder rumbling]
[ฟิาร้อง]
Do you want an umbrella?
เอาร่มไหม
It's raining.
ฝนตก
Hey!
เฮัย
[amusing music playing]
[ดนตรึตลกๆ]
What the hell?
อะไรวะ
Hey! Get it out of my face!
-เฮัย อะไรเนี่ย -เอาไปก่อน ออกไปดิ
Shit! Shit!
เฮัยๆ เฮัย
-Hey! -Shit!
-เฮัย
[both exclaiming]
[ทั้งคู่ตะโกน]
[thunder rumbling]
[ฟิาร้อง]
[both coughing]
[ทั้งคู่ไอ]
[rain pattering]
[ฝนตก]
[thunder rumbling]
[ฟิาร้อง]
I'm sorry.
เราขอโทษนะ
I told you it's okay.
บอก เเสํวไงวําไม่ เปิ้นไร
Go line up.
ไป เซํา เเถว เห อะ
I'll wait for you.
เติ่ยวเราเซําสายพร้อมนายก็ไตํ
Whatever suits you.
ตามโจละก๊น
I'm Dew from Class 3.
เราซึ่อดิว อยู่หัองสามนะ
[slow instrumental music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
I'm Phop from Class 5.
เราภพ หัองหัา
Phop.
ภพ
You can wear this.
นายเอาซุดนื้ไปใลํก่อนก็ไตํนะ
No, it's fine.
เฮัย ไม่เปิ้นไร
I'll wear my uniform after I clean it.
เติ่ยวเราสํางซุดเสร็จเรา ก็ใลํไปเรึยนไตํเเสํว
Nonsense.
ไม่ เปิ้นไรบ๋า อะไรล่ะ
Your uniform will be soaking wet.
ซุดนายมันก็ไม่ไตํจะเเหังตํวยนะ
Here.
-อือ -เฮัย
Believe me.
เซึ่อ เรา
I said it's okay.
ก็บอกวําไม่เปิ้นไรไง เกรงใจ
I will wash this for you.
เติ่ยวเอากล์บไปซ้กใหั
You gave me this.
เเสํวนายเอาซุดนื้มาใหั เรา
What will you wear?
นายจะไป เรึยนทั้งอย่างงี้เลย เหรอ
Dew.
ดิว
-[lilting music playing] -Are you really going to wear this?
[ดนตรึตลกๆ] ดิว มึงจะใลํซุดนื้เซําเรึยนจริงๆ เหรอวะ
Of course.
เออ ซุดนื้เเห ละ
Why?
ทําไมวะ
Why don't you wear a gym suit?
กุวํามึงเอาซุดพละมาเปลิ่ยนเถอะ
Otherwise Mr. Thanom will scold you in dance class.
ถัามึงย์งไม่อยากโดนถนอมด่าในคาบลีลาศน่ะ
Why would he do that?
ด่าทําไมวะ
This is similar to a gym suit.
นื่ก็ซุดกืฬาเหมีอนก๊น
Gym suit, my ass!
ซุดกืฬาบ๋าอะไรของมึงวะ
It's for Sports Day.
กืฬาลีไงมึง
Ready, cheerleaders?
ลีดพร้อม
[Dew] Three, four...
[ตีว] สาม ลิ่
[all clap rhythmically]
หนื่ง สอง หนื่ง สอง สาม หนื่ง สอง หนื่ง สอง หนื่ง
Awesome!
โคตรจ๋าบ
[all laughing]
[ทุกคนหืว เราะ]
[announcer speaking] Attention, students.
[เลียงประกาศ] สวีสดืครึบน็กเรึยนทุกคน
I have something
ครูมีเริ่อง
to announce.
ที่อยากจะเเจังใหัพวกเราทราบ
Currently,
ตํวยขณะนื้
AIDS has been
เมีองปางน้อยของเรา
spreading around Pang Noi town.
มี การเเพวี่ระบาดข อง เซึอ เอดลักืนเปิ้นอ ย่างมาก
Especially among homosexual men.
โดยเฉพาะในกลุ่ม
-[crowd muttering indistinctly] -Our county has
-[พุดคุยพึมพํา] -[เลียงประกาศ] ทางอําเภออะ
asked us to organize a training session
จืงขอใหัทางโรงเรึยนของเรา
for the homosexual students.
[ดนตรึลืกลืบ]
We have many experts
ทางโรงเรึยนไตํจีดวิทยากร
such as psychiatrists and soldiers.
ซึ่งมีทั้ง
So the students who are homosexual,
ดืงนี๊น จืงขอโหัน็กเรึยน
please come and register.
ออกมาลงทะเบียน
[students muttering]
[พูดคุยพึมพํา]
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึจริงจีง]
[announcer speaking] All teachers
[เลียงประกาศ] คุณครูครึบ ครูประจําซํน
and student inspectors,
สารวีตรน็กเรึยนครึบ ฑยตูตํวย
please bring those concerned out here.
จ์บออกมาเลยครึบ
Please.
นะคร้บ
-What's your name? -Thanawat.
-ซึ่ออะไรครึบ -ธนวีฒน์
[announcer speaking] You will receive instruction
[เลียงประกาศ] เราจะไตํรึบความรู้ครึบ
from these experts and psychiatrists.
จากวิทยากรตํวยนะครึบ
Also soldiers...
[เลียงประกาศเบาลง] ทหารตํวยนะครึบมาอบรมใหั เรา
[announcer speaking softly]
นะครึบ เราจะไตัรู้วํา
[pleasant music playing]
[ดนตรึสบายๆ]
Mom!
เเม่
I'm home.
กล์บมาเเสํวนะ
[Mom] You're here.
[เเม่] กสํบมาเเสํวเหรอ
Want some oranges?
กึนลัมไหมลูก
Why are you dressed like this?
ทําไม เเตํงดืวอย่างเงี้ย
Why not?
ทําไม อะ
What's in that bag?
อ่าว เเสํวนั่นถุงอะไร ซํางหล์ง
My friend's uniform.
ถุงเสิ้อเพี่อนอะเเม่
-Well, today-- -I know.
-พ อดืวีนนื้ดิว... -รู้เเสํว
You and your friend had an accident this morning.
เมี่อเซัซ้อนรถเต็กเเถวนื้ไปเเสํวรถสํมใซ่ไหม
How did you know?
เเม่รู้ไตํไงอะ
Everyone knows, Dew.
เขาก็รู้ก๊นทึ่วไหมดิว
You crashed into someone's paddy.
รถพวก เเกนื่ลงไปโนนาซําวฑวบัานเขานะ
Now what?
เเสํว ย์งไง
Are you going to wash his clothes?
จะเอาเสิ้อเขามาซ้กใหั
I won't do it for you.
เเม่ไม่ซ้กใหันะ
Well...
เตี่ยว
I'll do it myself.
ดิวซ้กเองก็ไตํ
Oh, my!
โณ์ห
You don't even wash your own clothes.
เลือ ผัาดืวเองไม่ เหึนเคยคิดจะซ้ก เลย
But you will do it for him?
ทืเสิ้อเพี่อนนื่จะซ้กใหั
-Oh, God! -Well, I made him crash his bike.
-เจริญ -ก็ดิวอะ
I don't want to hear.
ไม่อยากฟีงเเสํว
-Mom! -[Mom] Get up early tomorrow.
-เเม่อะ -[เเม่] พรุ่งนีตืนเซัๆ
I'll give you a ride.
[เเม่] เเสํวก็ออกไปพร้อมก๊น
[crickets chirping]
[จี๋งหรึดร้อง]
[tableware jingling]
[ภาซนะกระทบ]
Here's tea.
[พุดภาษาจืน] เอัานี่ นิ้าฑ
Oh, Phop.
อัาว อาภพ
Where is your uniform?
[พุดภาษาจืน] ซุดน็กเรึยนไปไหนลํะ
My friend ruined it.
[พุดภาษาจืน] เพี่อนผมท่าเลอะ
So he offered to wash it for me.
[พุดภาษาจืน] เขาก็เลยเอาไปซ้กใหั
Does he know how to wash clothes?
[พุดภาษาจืน] เขาซ้กผัาเปิ้นเหรอ
They might be better at it
[พุดภาษาจืน] พวกเขาอาจซ้กดืกวํา
than you are.
[พุดภาษาจืน] เธอก็ไตํ
[chuckles softly]
หึ
Just eat.
[พุดภาษาจืน] กึนซําว
[speaking Thai] Dew, hurry.
ดิวเร็วๆ ลูก
Yes, Mom.
ครีบ เเม่
[fabric shaking]
[สะบัด ฝ้า]
[school bell chiming]
[กั้ริ่ง]
[pleasant music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
Dew!
ดิว
Not going home yet?
คี่าเเสํวย์งไม่กล์บอีกเหรอวะ
Waiting for my mom.
รอเเม่อะ
She's running late.
เเม่กุมาตี่าๆ
I see.
อ่อ
I can give you a ride.
มึงจะใหักุไปลํงปะ
No, it's fine.
เฮัย ไม่เปิ้นไร
[amusing music playing]
[ดนตรึตลกๆ บรรเลง]
Oh!
เฮีย
You can give me a ride, but wait a second.
ไปลํงกุก็ไตํ เเตํรอกุเเปืบน็งนะ
Hey!
เฮัย
Actually, I can't.
จริงๆ อะ กุไปลํงมึงไม่ไตํเเสํวนะ
Why did you ask me then?
เเสํวมึงถามกุทําไมวะ
I was trying to be nice.
ก็กุถามเปิ้นมารยาทไง
Asshole!
ไอัเหี้ยนี่
Sorry.
โทษทื
I want to return your uniform.
เราเอาเลีอที่เอาไปครื้งที่เเสํวมาคืนน่ะ
Are you in a rush? Wait a second.
รึบไหม รอเเปืบน็งนะ
I'm not in a rush.
ไม่รึบหรอก
You?
นายล่ะ
I'm about to go home.
จะกล์บเเสํวอะ
But I don't know how I'm getting there.
เเต่ยํงไม่รู้จะกล์บยํงไงเลยอะ
You said your mom's picking you up.
มึงบอกเเม่มึงจะมารึบไม่ใซ่เหรอ
I'm still deciding.
ก็กุสํงเลอยู่ไง
What's wrong with you?
มึงซ็เรึยสอะไรของมึงเนี่ย
[engine accelerating]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[man shouting] Get off!
[ผุ้ฑยตะโกน] ลงๆ
Go home! Quick!
-กล์บบ๋าน โหัไวๆ -เดินเร็วๆ
Quickly!
ไวๆ ดิ
Come on!
เร็ว
Go home!
ไปๆ
Go! Go!
-ไปๆ ไป
Quickly!
ใหั ไว
[melancholic music playing]
[ดนตรึเศร้าๆ บรรเลง]
Thank you for this. I'm going home now.
ขอบคุณมากนะ เดิ่ยวเรากลืบก่อนนะ
Attention, students.
อะน็กเรึยน เรึยบร้อยหน่อยครึบ
[students chatting]
[เต็กๆ คุยก๊น]
[teacher] Today Mrs. Thanomchit went to a seminar.
[ครู] วีนนื้ครูถนอมจืตไปอบรม
So did Miss Kaew from Class 5.
เหมี อนก๊บหัองของครูเเกัวหัองหัา เลย
So Class 5 will join us
ครูก็เลยเอาลองหัองมาเรึยนรวม กัน
for PE class.
โนวิฑพลศึกษา
You all know each other, right?
ลองหัองรู้จีก ก๊นนะครึบ
-Yes. -Great.
-รู้จ์ก -โอ เค
[students mumbling]
[พูดคุยพึมพํา]
[pleasant music playing]
[ดนตรึลบายๆ]
Hey!
เฮัย
You will pair up for dance practice.
เติ่ยวเราจะเซําคู่ก๊นเเสํวนะ
So boys will pair up with boys
วีนนื้จ์บคู่ก๊นในล์กษณะ ฑย ฑย
and girls with girls.
หญิงก๊บหญิง
So it won't violate our tradition.
เพี่อไม่ใหัผิดผีก๊น
[giggles]
[หืวเราะคืกคืก]
[teacher] Ready?
[ครู] พร้อม
Please pair up!
จํบคู่คร้บ
[shoes squeaking]
[รองเทําเสิ่ยดสิ่]
Hey! Do you have a partner?
เฮัย มึง มีคู่ย์ง
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
-Oh! -Hi, Phop.
-อัาว -หวีดดืภพ
Hi, Dew.
หวีดดื ดิว
Well...
เอิ่ม
Do you have a partner yet?
มีคู่หรึอยํงอะ
Not yet.
ย์งเลยอะ
Today we will practice the cha-cha dance.
วีนนื้นะ เราจะทบทวนโนจ์งหวะซะซะฆั
Look at your friends if you can't follow the steps.
ใครที่ไม่ไตํ ตูเพี่อน
Music!
เพลงมา
So, you're a girl?
ลรุปนายเปิ้นผู้หญิงใซ่ไหม
What? No.
เอัย ไม่ใซ่
I'm not.
เฮีย โซ่ดิ
What is it then?
ลรุปยํงไงก๊นเเน่เนื่ย
I'm...
เปิ้น
a guy who can do a woman's moves.
เปิ้นผุ้ฑยที่เตันท่า ผุ้หญิงเเสํวก๊น
[cha-cha music playing]
[ดนตรึจีงหวะเร็ว]
[music increases in tempo]
[ดนตรึจ์งหวะเร็วขี้น]
-Sorry. -It's okay.
-ขอโทษ -ไม่ เปิ้นไร
Look at my face!
เเต่มองมาที่หน้าเราดิ
Why?
ทําไม อะ
Just do it.
มองมาที่หน้าเเล์วอะ
Then look into my eyes.
โหัมองมาที่ตานะ
You will know the rhythm.
จะรู้จ์งหวะก๊นเอง
Yeah?
เหรอ
[music increases in tempo]
[ดนตรึจ์งหวะเร็วขี้น]
I'm really sorry.
ขอโทษนะ
About what?
เริ่องอะไรเหรอ
I scrubbed your shirt too hard.
เรา เเปรงคอเลือนายเเรงไปหน่อย
It's torn.
ขาดหมดเลย
Don't worry.
ไม่ เปิ้นไรหรอก
Well, actually,
เออ จะวําไป
I haven't returned your gym suit.
เราก็ยํงไม่ไตํคืนเสิ้อพละนายเลยอะ
It's fine. Don't worry.
เฮัย ไม่เปิ้นไร ไม่ชีเรึยส
You can return it to me anytime.
เลร็จเมี่อไหรค่อยเอามาคืนก็ไตํ
[piano music playing]
[ดนตรึโรเเมนติ๋กบรรเลง]
[students chatting]
[เลียงถุงกระดาษ]
[Phop] Sit down.
[ผุ้ฑย] นั่งก่อนดิ
Can I lay my head on your lap?
ขอหนุนหน่อยนะ กุงวง
Guess what's in this picture?
ทายเร็ว รูปนื้รูปอะไร
What is it?
คืออะไรอะ
I don't know.
ไม่รู้เวัย
There is
รูป เนื้ย
a whale in it.
มีปลาวาฬซ่อนอยู่
Huh?
ฮะ
What?
อะ
Where's the whale?
ไหนวะปลาวาฬ
It's in there.
มันมีจริงๆ
Want me to teach you?
ลอนใหัเอาไหม
Yeah.
เอาดิ
Raise your forefinger.
ยกนิ้วซี้ขี้นมาก่อน
Keep staring at it.
เเสํวก็เฟงลายตาไปที่นิ้วซึนะ
And then slowly look at the picture.
จากนี๊นก็ค่อยๆ เลิ่อน
See it?
เหึนไหม
Can't see it yet?
โอัย ยํงไม่เหึนอีกเหรอ
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
So...
อํา เเสํว
What is it then?
ลรุปมันคือรูปอะไรเหรอ
There's a shrimp in here.
มันมีกุ๊งกัามกรามซ่อนอยู่อะ
Really?
จริง เหรอวะ
[Phop] Anyway,
[ภพ] จะวําไป
do you prefer Pang Noi or Chiang Mai?
ที่นื่ก๊บเซึยงใหม่ ดิวซอบที่ไหนมากกวําก๊นเหรอ
[Dew] I'm not sure.
บอกไม่ถูกอะ
Chiang Mai is more civilized.
เเต่โนเมีองมันก็เจริญกวํา
There's lots of things to do.
มีอะไรใหัทําเยอะกวํา
[Phop] So you don't like it here.
เเลดงวําก็ไม่ซอบที่นี่เหรอ
[Dew] Not really.
ก็ไม่เซิงไม่ซอบหรอก
Maybe...
เเต่...
I still can't adjust to this town.
อาจจะยํงปรึบดืวไม่ค่อยไตํมั้ง
Don't worry about me.
เเตํภพไม่ตัองห่วงนะ
Do you want to go to Chiang Mai?
เเสํวภพอยากไปเซึยงใหม่ไหม
[pleasant music playing]
[ดนตรึลบายๆ]
[engine revs]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[music increases in tempo]
[ดนตรึจ์งหวะเร็วขี้น]
[man] All done.
[ผุ้ฑยพูด] เลร็จเรึยบร้อยเเสํวนะครึบ
[music continues]
[ดนตรึเลนตํอ]
[sneezes]
[จาม]
Stop messing around.
อัาว อย่าเลนก๊นสิ่คะ
Before finishing class today,
ก่อนจะจากก๊นวีนนื้นะลูก
I want to tell you about a campaign from the New Zealand Academy.
ครูมีกึจกรรมดืๆ
You'll pick a Thai song and translate it into English.
ก็คือโหัเราไปหาเพลงไทย
Make it smooth and beautiful.
โหัมี ความ สละสลวย
The winner will receive a free summer trip to New Zealand.
หากโครเปิ้นผุ้ซนะ
[all exclaiming]
[ทุกคนลํง เลียง]
Phop.
ภพ
New Zealand.
นีวซ็เเลนดฑ์
Bungee jump.
บ๋นจืจีมป์
It's difficult.
มันยากนะเวัย
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[groans]
[ครางํ]
Phop.
ภพ
Come on, take me to the convenience store.
เร็ว พาไปเซเวํนหน่อย
[engine revs]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
No, I don't want to steer it.
ไม่เอาอะ
Come on. Give it a try.
เอาน่า ลองตูก่อน
Come on.
มา
No.
ไม่ เอา
Why can't you just give me a ride like usual?
ภพไปลํงดิวเหมีอนทุกทืมันก็ดือยู่เเสํวอะ
Don't be stubborn.
อย่าตี้อสิ่
So you can go get something to eat
นื่ไป์ เวลาภพนอนตอนกลางคืน
when I sleep at night.
เเสํวดิวอยากออกไปหาอะไรกึนจะไตํซํบไปไตัไง
Come on.
อะเร็ว
Here.
นื่
Now,
เลร็จ เเสํวก็
use your right foot.
เอาขาขวา
Yes.
อือ
Now push it down.
ทืนื้ก็ดืนลงไป
[engine starts]
[เคริ่องยนตฑ์ลํง เลียง]
Harder!
เเรงอีกนึด
-Harder! Harder! -[engine revving]
-เเรงกวํานื้ๆ -[เครึองยนตฑ์ลํง เลียง]
-Ouch! -Oh!
-โอี ย
Are you okay?
เปิ้นอะไรปะเนี่ย
I'm fine.
ไม่ เปิ้นไรๆ
Push it down.
ดืนลงไปอีก
[engine spluttering]
[เคริ่องยนตฑ์ลํง เลียง]
More!
ลงไปอีก
Harder!
เเรงๆ หน่อย
You almost got it.
เกือบไตํเเสํวๆ ดิว
[engine whirring]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
Okay.
โอ เค
Come sit.
มา
Don't be afraid.
ไม่ตํองกล์วๆ
Hold the handles.
เอามี อจีบ เเฮนดฑ์
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
Ready?
พร้อมไหม
One, two...
หนื่ง ลอง
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึจริงจีง]
-[Phop] Go! -[engine accelerating]
-[ภุพ] ไป -[เครึองยนตโ
Easy! Easy!
ค่อยๆ ปลอย ค่อยๆ ปลอย
Hey!
เฮัย
Are you all right?
เปิ้นอะไรไหม เนื่ย
[breathing heavily]
[หายใจ เเรง]
-Are you okay? It's okay. -Enough.
-เปิ้นอะไรไหม ไม่เปิ้นไร -ภพ พอเหอะ
Just give me a ride as usual.
ทุกทืภพไปลํงก็ดือยู่เเสํวอะ
Why do you want me to do it?
โหัดิวฝืนท่าไมวะ
Because sometimes I want to sleep.
ก็บางทืภพก็งวงอยากนอนอะดิว
You always drag me out of bed.
ดิวก็ลากออกไปตลอดเลยอะ
It's nothing.
ก็เเค่นื้เองอะ
Why can't you do it for me?
ทําใหัไม่ไตํเหรอ
Just give me a ride.
เเค่ขี่ไปใหั อะ
Can't you just go by yourself?
มึงหืดไปคนเดืยวบัางไม่เปิ้นหรึอไงวะ
Seriously...
กุถามจริงๆ เหอะ
you drag me out because
มึงลากกุออกไปทุกคืนอย่างงี้
you don't want me to rest, right?
กะจะไม่ใหักุนอนเลยใซ่ปะ
I'm fucking tired.
กุก็เหนื่อยเหมีอนก๊นนะเวัย
Leave if you're so tired.
ถัามึงเหนื่อย มึงก็กล์บไปดิ
Leave!
อยู่ทําไม
Why are you saying that?
ทําไมมึงพุดอย่างงี้วะ
Hey!
เฮัย
[melancholy music playing]
[ดนตรึเศร้าๆ บรรเลง]
This is how it's going to be?
มึงจะทําดืวอย่างปี๊ซ่ไหม
Leave!
กล์บไปดิ
You said it yourself.
มึงพูดเองนะ
[engine starts]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[engine accelerating]
[เรงเคริ่อง]
[thunder rumbling]
[ฟิาร้อง]
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[melancholic music playing]
[ดนตรึเศร้าๆ บรรเลง]
[engine spluttering]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[melancholic music continues]
[ดนตรึจ์งหวะเร็วขี้น]
[Phop] It's okay.
[ภพ] ไม่ เปิ้นไร
It's all right.
ไม่ เปิ้นไรนะ
I'm not angry.
ภพไม่โกรธ
See?
เหึนไหม
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[rain pattering]
[ฝนตก]
[door opens]
[ประตูเปิ้ด]
[door closes]
[ประตูปิ้ด]
[breathing heavily]
[หายใจ เสิ่ยงดืง]
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[sighs]
[หายโจออก]
I'm very pleased to tell you all that the winner of
[ผุ้หญิง] ครูมีความยินดื
the trip to New Zealand is...
ไตํไปนีวชีเเลนดฑ์
Mr. Krittaphop Saeyang.
นายกฤตภพ เเซ่หยางค่ะ
[clapping]
[ปรบมิ่ยิ]
A big round of applause, please.
ปรบมึอโหัเพี่อนหน่อยค่ะ
Congratulations!
คอนเเกรตจูเลซํนลัค่ะ
Krittaphop?
กฤตภพ ลูก
[mumbling]
[พูดคุยพึมพํา]
[teacher] Krittaphop!
[ควู๊] กฤตภพ
Please come up here and read your work.
ออกมาพรึเซนตโหัครูเเละเพี่อนฟีงหน่อยลูก
Come.
มาเลย
Very good. Come on. I'm so proud of you.
เก่งลูก มาเลยครึบ ครูภูมึโจที่ลุดเลยลูก
Come here.
มาเลยครึบ
[pleasant music playing]
[ดนตรึเพลงซับรรเลง]
[reading lyric in English] "Before the sky turns bright.
[อ่านเนื้อเพลงภาษาอืงกฤษ] บีฟอรัเดอะ ลกาย เหิรัน ไบรตฑ์
Before feeling the warmth of sunlight.
บีฟอรัฟืลลืง เดอะ วอรัมธฑ์ออฟ ซ้นไลตฑ์
Before the flowers bloom.
[อ่านเนื้อเพลงภาษาอืงกฤษ] บีฟอรัเดอะ ฟลาวเวอรัล บลูม
Before having a sweet dream.
บีฟอรั เเฮฟวิง อะ ลวีต ดรึม
I've never had anyone in my heart
[อ่านเนื้อเพลงภาษาอืงกฤษ] ไอ เนเวอรั เเฮด เอนึวีน อิน มาย ฮารัต
till your love came
หิล ย์วรัเลืฟ เคม
and made me see the brightness.
[อ่านเนื้อเพลงภาษาอืงกฤษ] เเอนดฑ์ เมด มี ซื เดอะ ไบรตในล
I've never had anyone beside me
[อานเนื้อเพลงภาษาอืงกฤษ] ไอ เนเวอรัเเฮด เอนึวีน บีไซดฑ์มี
till your crazy mercy came
หิล ยํวรั เครซ็ เมอรัซ็ เคม
and motivated me
[อานเนื้อเพลงภาษาอืงกฤษ] เเอนดฑ์โมหิเวต มี
to live...
ทุ ลืฟ
in this mad world."
[อานเนื้อเพลงภาษาอืงกฤษ] อิน ดีส เเมด เวิลดฑ์
[students chatting]
[น็กเรึยนพุดคุย]
Hey, Phat!
เฮัย ไอัพัฒน์
Come sit here.
นั่งนี่ดิ
How have you been?
เปิ้นไงบ๋างเนี่ย
[music stops]
[ดนตรึห ยุด เลน]
No one showed up?
คนอี่นมันโดดเวรก๊นเหรอวะ
[chalkboard screeching]
[เลียงเซ็ดกระดาน]
[brush banging]
[เเปรงกระเเทก]
What the fuck are you doing?
ทํา เหี้ ยอะไรของมึงเนี่ย
You won't talk to me.
ก็มึงไม่คุยก๊บกุอะ
Why won't you talk to me?
ทําไมมึงตํองไม่คุยก๊บกุตํวยวะ
You like me?
มึงคิดอะไรก๊บกุ
It's you...
ก็มึงเปลาวะ
that made me fall for you.
ที่ทําโหักุคิดอะไรก๊บมึงอะ
I don't care.
กุไม่รู้หรอก
But whatever happened between us,
เเตํไม่วําอะไรจะเกึดขึ้นก๊บเราอะ
it's impossible.
มันเปิ้นไปไม่ไตํหรอกเวัย
Can't we be friends?
เเสํวเราจะเปิ้นเพี่อนก๊นไม่ไตํเลยเหรอวะ
Do you really think we can just be friends?
มึงจะคิดก๊บกุเเค่เพี่อนไตํจริงๆ เหรอ
What about my dad?
ไหนจะฟอกุอีก
What about this damn school?
ไหนจะไณ์รงเรึยนเหี้ยนื่อีก
We'll keep it a secret.
เราก็อย่าโหัคนอี่นรู้สิ่ภพ
Dew, this is Pang Noi.
ดิว ที่นื่ปางน้อยนะเวัย
Everyone knows what we are.
มึงคิดวําคนอี่นเขาไม่รู้ก๊นเหรอวําเราเปิ้นย์งไง
We'll leave this place.
เราก็ไปจากที่นื่ก๊นดิ
Let's start over somewhere else!
ไป เริ่มตํนก๊นใหม่ที่อี่นก็ไตันะ
Enough.
มึงพอเหอะ
I'm not like you.
กุไม่ไตํเปิ้นเหมีอนมึงนะเวัย
What do you mean "not like me"?
เปิ้นเหมีอนกุหมายความวําไงวะ
Answer me!
มึงตอบมาดิ
What's wrong with "being like me"?
เหมึอนกุเเสํวมันทําไมอะ
[shouting] What the fuck do you mean?
[ตะโกน] มึงหมายความวําไงอะเหมีอนกุอะ
[shouting] I don't want to be an outcast like you.
[ตะโกน] ไม่อยากโดนส์งคมรึงเกืยจเหมีอนมึงไง
I want to be like everyone else.
กุอยากเปิ้นเหมีอนคนอี่น มึงเซําโจกุไหม
Asshole!
ไอัเหี้ยภพ
Do you think I want to be like this?
มึงคิดวํากุอยากเปิ้นอย่างงี้มากเหรอวะ
[table banging]
[โต๊ะกระเเทก]
[indistinct chatter]
[คุยพึมพํา]
Hey! Dew!
เฮัย ไอัดิว ดิว
[indistinct shouting]
-[คุยพึมพํา] -พอไตํเเสํว ดิว
[man] The witness said that Dew started it.
จากคนที่เหึนเหตุการณ์
I'd like to know...
ครูอยากทราบ
the reason.
ลาเหตุเกึดจากอะไร
Phop,
ภพเอง
you yelled at Dew,
ก็ไปตะโกนใลํดิววํา
"I don't want to be an outcast like you.
กุไม่อยากโดนส์งคมรึงเกืยจ
I don't want to be like you."
กุไม่อยากเปิ้นเหมีอนมึง
What does that mean?
อะไรเหรอ ภพ
Why did you call him an outcast?
ที่ทําใหัภพคืดวําส์งคมร้งเกืยจ
Say what you have to say!
[ตะโกนภาษาจืน] มีอะไรก็พุดไป
I'm going home.
[ตะโกนภาษาจืน] ฟอกล์บบ๋านเเสํว
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[engine revs]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[Dew in Thai] Mom.
[ตีว] เเม่
[sobbing]
[สะอื้น]
[Dew] If I'm gay,
[ดิว] ถัาดิวเปิ้นเเบบนื้
will you still love me?
เเม่จะย์งรึกดิวอยู่หรึอเปลา
[melancholic music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
Why won't you fight back?
[ฟอภพพูดภาษาจืน] ทําไมถีงไม่สู้กลืบ
A faggot hit you.
[ตะโกนภาษาจืน] ตุ้ดต่อยเเก
Where's your honor? You're a disgrace.
[ตะโกนภาษาจืน] เกืยรตืเเกอยู่ที่ไหน
Pa, calm down, take it easy.
[ภาษาจืน] ฟอ โจเยึนๆ ก่อน
-This little fucker. -Pa, calm down.
-[ตะโกนภาษาจืน] ไอัเวร -ฟ อใจเยีน
Take it easy.
[ภาษาจืน] โจเยึน
I'm so pissed.
[ภาษาจืน] ฉืนโมโหมาก
[girl in Thai] Everyone knows that you are gay.
[ผุ้หญิง] เขารู้ก๊นทั้งโรงเรึยนเเสํวอะวํามึงเปิ้น
[Dew] I thought you already knew.
[ฝุ่ฑย] กุคิดวําพวกมึงรู้อยู่เเสํวซะอีกอะ
[girl] Kind of.
[ผุ้หญิง] พอจะรู้อะ
But that's not all they talk about.
เเต่... คนอี่นเขาไม่ไตํคุยก๊นเเค่นี๊นอะ
They said that you...
เขาบอกวํามึงอะ...
forced Phop to sleep with you.
ไปบ๋งคืบโหัไอัภพมีอะไรก๊น
[girl 2] But Phop didn't give in,
[ผุ้หญิง] เเสํวไอัภพไม่ยอมก็เลย...
so that's why you guys fought.
ตืก๊นในหัองเรึยนน่ะ
[students chatting]
[น็กเรึยนพุดคุย]
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึจริงจีง]
[pager beeping]
[เพจเจอรัดืง]
[birds chirping]
[นกร้อง]
You told everyone that I tried to sleep with you?
มึงไปบอกคนอี่นเหรอวํากุจะท่าอะไรมึงอะ
No, I didn't.
กุไม่ไตํบอก
I guess the teacher assumed it
ครูปกครองมันคงลมมุติ๋ของมันไปเองอะ
and told other people.
เเสํวมันไปบอกคนอี่นวํางั้น
You know what happened to my life, right?
มึงฮู้ซ่ไหม
I'm sorry.
กุขอโทษ
[sobbing]
[สะอื้น]
We can't be the same anymore.
มันกสํบมาเปิ้นเหมีอนเดิมไม่ไตํเเสํวนะเวัย
[crying]
[ริ้องไหวุ
Then why did you ask me to come?
เเสํวมึงจะอยากมาเจอกุทําเหี้ยอะไรอีกอะ
What do you want from me?
มีงตัองการอะไรจากกุ
Give me your wallet.
เอากระเปาดืงคฑ์มึงมา
Why do you want it?
มึงจะเอาไปทําไม
Just give it to me.
เอามาก่อน
-Are you going to rob me? -Come on. Quickly!
-มึงจะปสํนกุเหรอ -เอามาก่อน เร็วๆ
People said that...
พวกนี๊นบอกวํา
they only check a student card at training camp.
ที่ศูนยใขาตรวจเเตํบ๋ตรน็กเรึยน
I'll go in your place.
เติ่ยวภพไป เเทนดิว เอง
It'll be like training corps.
มันก็เหมีอนฝืก รด. เเทนก๊นนั่นเเหละ
[melancholic music playing]
[ดนตรึเศร้าๆ บรรเลง]
You're crazy.
บัา
Why are you doing this?
ทําไม เเบบนื้ทําไม
[sobbing]
[สะอื้น]
You don't have to go.
ภพไม่ตํองไปก็ไตันะ
Just stay like this.
เเค่อยู่เเบบนื้
We can be friends or whatever.
ฐานะอะไรก็ไตํ
[crying]
[ริ้องไหวุ
[pleasant music playing]
[ดนตรึลบายๆ]
[engine accelerating]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[shouting] Get off!
[ตะโกน] ลงๆ
[Dew] Let's run away together.
ดิววําเราไปจากที่นี่ก๊นเถอะ
[Phop] Where will we go?
จะไปไหนอะดิว
[Dew] Anywhere but Pang Noi.
ไปไหนก็ไตัอะ
We will take a train.
เราจะนั่งรถไฟออกไปจากที่นื่
Go without a plan.
ไป เเบบไม่มีจุดหมาย
Get off wherever we want.
อยากลงที่ไหนก็ลง
[Phop] What would our families say?
เเสํวที่บ๋านเราจะวําก๊นย๊งไงอะ
Would they still love us...
ที่เราเปิ้นเเบบนื้อะ
for who we are?
เขาย์งเหึนเราเปิ้นลูกอีกเหรอวะ
[pleasant music playing]
[ดนตรึเพลงซับรรเลง]
[engine revving]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[engine accelerating]
[เรงเคริ่อง]
Phop.
[ฟอภพพูดภาษาจืน] ภพ
Come here.
[ฟอภพพูดภาษาจืน] มานี่
Pa.
[เเม่ภพพุดภาษาจืน] ฟอ
Take it easy. Calm down.
[ภาษาจืน] โจเยึนๆ
My friend at camp told me
[ภาษาจืน] เพี่อนฟอที่ค่ายบอกมา
that you went for treatment.
[ภาษาจืน] วําเเกไปบําบ๋ด
What does that mean?
[ภาษาจืน] หมายความวําไง
Who sent you there?
[ภาษาจืน] ใครลํงเเกไปที่นั่น
[shouting] Tell me! Who sent you there?
[ภาษาจืน] บอกมา ใครลํงเเกไปที่นั่น
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
Last time,
[ภาษาจืน] ครื้งที่เเสํว
you didn't fight back.
[ภาษาจืน] เเกไม่สู้ตอบโตั
This time you joined the military for him.
[ภาษาจืน] ครื้งนี๊ เเกไปเซําค่ายทหารเเทนมัน
You tell me...
[ภาษาจืน] บอกฉีนมา
-Did he force you to do that? -Pa.
-[ภาษาจืน] มันบ๋งคืบเเกเหรอ -[เเม่ภพพูดภาษาจืน] ฟอ
-Is that right?
-[ภาษาจืน] ใซ่ไหม
It's a shame that I raised a son like you.
[ภาษาจืน] น่าอายที่ฉืนมีลูกฑยอย่างเเก
-You little fucker. -Pa.
-[ภาษาจืน] ไอัเวร -[เเม่ภพพูดภาษาจืน] ฟอ
That's enough.
[ภาษาจืน] พอเเสํว
Don't you take his side. You raised a coward.
[ภาษาจืน] อย่าเซําซํางมืน เเกเลื้ยงคนขี้ขลาดมา
He couldn't even fight a faggot.
[ภาษาจืน] เเมัเเต่ก๊บตุ้ดย์งไม่คิดสู้
I'll beat his sorry ass to hell.
[ภาษาจืน] ฉืนจะตืเเกใหัตาย
You want to be a faggot like him?
[ภาษาจืน] เเกอยากเปิ้นตุ้ดเหมีอนมืนเหรอ
You want to be as useless as him?
[ภาษาจืน] เเกอยากไร้ค่าเหมีอนมันเหรอ
Enough!
[ภาษาจืน] พอเเสํว
[in Thai] Enough, asshole!
พ อไตํเเสํวไอัส์ตวฑ์
[man] What did you do?
[ฝุ่ฑย] ภพทําอะไรป๊าอะ
He's your dad.
ปืานะเวัย
[crying]
-[ร้องไหปิ่ -พอ
He told me to fight!
ก็ปืาบอกใหัสูไง
Do you really want to know
พวกมึงอยากรู้ก๊นน็กใซ่ไหม
why I went to a training camp for Dew?
วําทําไมกุถีงไปเเทนไอัดิวอะ
Could you handle it if you knew?
มึงรู้เเสํวมึงจะรึบก๊นไตํไหม
Watch your mouth!
ไอัภพมึงพุดดืๆ
I have nothing to say.
ไม่มี เหี้ ย อะไรจะพูด เเสํว
[melancholic music playing]
[ดนตรึเศร้าๆ บรรเลง]
Shove it up yours and die.
[ตะโกนภาษาจืน] เเกไปตายซะไป
[crying hysterically] Please don't go!
[ร้องไหัหน็ภ] อย่าไปนะลูภ ภพ
Stop crying. He's not my son anymore.
[ตะโภนภาษาจืน] หยุดร้องไตํเเสํว
If you take a step outside...
[ตะโภนภาษาจืน] ถัาเเภกัาวขาออภไป
[engine accelerating]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
we're through.
[ตะโภนภาษาจืน] เราขาดก๊น
[Phop's mom shouting] Phop!
[เเม่ภพตะโภน] ภพ
[in Thai] Phop! Come back!
ภพ ภล์บมาก่อน
[Phop's mom crying hysterically]
[เเม่ภพร้องไหัหน็ภ]
[pager beeping]
[เสิ่ยงเพจเจอรัดืง]
[Phop] "You were right.
[ภพ] ดิวพูดถูภ
We should run away together.
เราควรจะไปจาภที่นื่ก๊นไตํเเสํว
The last train will leave
คืนนื้มันยํงมีรถไฟเที่ยวลุดท้ายอยู่
at 11:30 p.m. tonight.
ตอนหัาทุ่มคริ่ง
Let's go together!
เราไปตํวยก๊นนะ
From Phop."
จาภภพ
[sighs wearily]
[ถอนหายใจ]
What are you doing?
เเม่ทําอะไรอะ
Come talk to me.
ออภไปคุยก๊บเเม่ซํางนอภ
What's your relationship with Phop?
ดิวก๊บภพเปิ้นอะไรก๊น
We're just friends.
เปิ้นเพี่อนก๊นเเม่
Where are you planning to go?
เเสํวจะไปไหนก๊นอะ
Give it back and I'll tell you.
เอาคืนมาก่ อนเเสํวจะบอภ
[pager beeps]
[เสิ่ยงเเจังเตือนจาภเพจเจอปิ๊
Can you tell me?
บอภเเม่ไตํหรึอย๊ง
Where are you going?
วําจะไปไหนก๊น
Anywhere
ไปที่ไหนก็ไตัอะ
but Pang Noi.
ที่ไม่ใซ่ที่นี่อะ
Why?
ทําไม อะลูภ
Don't you know?
เเม่ ยํงจะถามอืภเหรอ
Do you have an answer for me yet?
เเม่ตอบดิวไตํหรึอยํงอะ
If I'm gay,
ถัาดิวเปิ้นเเบบนื้อะ
will you still love me?
เเม่จะย์งรึภดิวอยู่หรึอเปลา
Of course I do.
ก็รึภสิ่
I will love you no matter what you are.
ดิวจะเปิ้นอะไรเเม่ก็รึภทั้งนี๊นเเหละ
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[phone ringing]
[โทรคืพทฑ์ดืง]
You're all I have.
เรามีก๊นอยู่ลองคนนะดิว
If you leave, I will be alone.
[โทรคืพทฑ์ดืงตํอ] ถัาดิวไปเเลัวเเม่จะอยู่ก๊บใครอะ
You can be whatever you want.
ดิวจะเปิ้นอะไรก็ไตํ
Just please don't leave me.
ขออย่างเดืยวอย่าไปจาภที่นี่ไตํไหม
Can I really be whatever I want here?
ดิวอยู่ที่นื่เปิ้นอะไรก็ไตํจริงๆ เหรอเเม่
You sent me to behavioral therapy.
เเม่เพิ่งเซ็นโหัดิวไปบําบ๋ดพฤตีภรรมนะ
If I came out, I would be expelled.
เเม่จะไปเเภไหัดิวโดนไลออภ เหรอ
Can you handle that?
เเม่รึบไตํเหรอ
I will do everything for you.
ใหั เเม่ทํา อะไรก็ไตํ อะดิว
The only thing I ask
เเม่ขออย่างเดืยว
is for you not to leave.
อย่าไปไตํไหม
You can love any man in this world.
ดิวจะรึภ ผุ้ฑยกี่คนในโลภนื้ก็ไตํ
But can the only woman you love be me?
เเตํ ผุ้หญิงคนเดียวที่ดิวจะร้ภ
Please.
ไตํไหมลูภ
[phone continues ringing]
[โทรคืพทฑ์ดืง]
[sobbing]
[สะอื้น]
Hello.
ฮี้ลโหล
[Phop] Dew, what were you doing?
[ภพ] ดิว ทําอะไรอยู่อะ
Sorry, I was in the shower.
[ดิว] โทษทือะ ตะกี๊อาบนิ้าอยู่
How's things at home?
ภพภล์บบ๋านไปเเสํวเปิ้นไงบ๋างอะ
My dad knew about the training camp.
ปืาจ์บไตํเริ่องที่เราไปเเทนดิวอะ
He disowned me.
[ภพ] ดืดพอดืดลูภก๊นไปเเสํวเนื่ย
Are you serious?
พูดจริงปะเนี่ย
Yes.
[ภพ] จริง
When he found out that I'm gay,
พ อ เขารู้วํา เรา เปิ้นอะไร
he cut me off.
เขา ก็ไม่รึบ เรา เปิ้นลูภ เเสํว อะ
I think...
[ภพ] ภพวํา...
I will leave tonight.
ภพจะไปคืนนื้เลยอะ
Come with me.
ดิวไปก๊บภพนะ
Does it have to be tonight?
มันด่วนไปไหมอะภพ
I think tonight is perfect.
ภพวําตอนนี๊ก็เหมาะที่ลุดเเสํวนะดิว
I can't go tonight.
มันยํงไม่ใฑีนนื้อะ
You mean you're not coming?
หมายความวําดิวจะไม่ไปงั้นเหรอ
I'm sorry.
เราขอโทษนะ
But I can't leave my mom.
เเต่เเม่เราอยู่คนเดืยวอะ
If I leave, she will be all alone.
ถัาเราไปเเสํวเเภจะอยู่ก๊บใครอะ
Phop?
ฮี้ลโหล ภพ
Hello?
ฮี้ลโหล
[Phop] You told me
[ภพ] มึงเปิ้นคนบอภกุเองนะดิว
that we would run away together.
วําเราจะไปตํวยก๊น
But you changed your mind because of your mom?
เเตํพอเเม่มึงขอโหัไม่ไปมึงก็ไม่ไปอย่างเงี้ยอะเหรอ
-[banging] -My dad fucking disowned me!
[ทุบโทรคืพทโ กุโดนดืดพอดืดลูภนะเวัย
Everything I did.
ทุภอย่างที่กุทํา
Everything I sacrificed.
ที่กุยอมลละไป
So I could be with you!
ก็เพี่อใหัไตํอยู่ก๊บมึงเนี่ย
I'm really sorry.
เราขอโทษนะ
Your apology doesn't mean shit.
ขอโทษเเสํวมันไตํ เหี้ ย อะไรซื้นมาวะ
Can you bring back what I've lost?
มึงเอาลิ่งที่กุเลียไปเเสํวภล์บคืนมาไตัไหมละ
-Phop, listen to me. -Just...
-ภพฟีงเราก่อนนะ -ไม่ฟีงอะ
Forget about everything.
มึงลืมมันไปซะเถอะ
I was nice to you...
ที่กุเคยทําดืก๊บมึง
[sobbing]
[สะอื้น]
...because I pitied you.
กุก็เเค่ลงลารมึงเท่านี๊นเเหละ
[crying hysterically]
[ร้องไหัหน็ภ]
[engine accelerating]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[melancholic music playing]
[ดนตรึเศร้าๆ บรรเลง]
[sobbing]
[สะอื้น]
[train approaching]
[บีบ เเต ร]
[announcer speaking] The train is arriving at platform one.
[ประภาศ] รถไฟ เซําลู่ลถานี โนฑนฑลาทืหน็งกําลืงเซํามา
Train approaching, please be careful.
[ประภาศ] ระวังอืนตรายจาภขบวนรถตํวยนะครึบ
Train approaching, please be careful.
[ประภาศ] โปรดระมัดระวีงอืนตราย จาภขบวนรถตํวยนะครึบ
[bell dinging]
[เสิ่ยงภริ่ง]
[train approaching]
[เสิ่ยงรถไฟ]
PANG NOI
[นภร้อง]
[rooster crowing]
[ไก่ซํน]
Ready for your first day?
วีนเเรภไหวนะ
Of course.
ลบายอยู่เเสํว
[laughing]
[หื ว เรา อื]
What about you?
เเสํวภพอะจะไหวปะ
I'll be fine.
สบาย
Good luck!
โหย สู้ๆ
-See you later! -Yes.
-เจอก๊น -จัะ
[car door closes]
[ประตูปิ้ด]
[school bell ringing]
[เสิ่ยงออดเซําเรึยน]
My name is Phop
ครูซึ่อภพนะคร้บ
and I will be your homeroom teacher.
มาเปิ้นครูประจําซํนหัองมอลิ่ทํบลาม
This will also be my first class.
เเสํววีนนื้ครูก็มาลอนที่นี่หัองนื้เปิ้นที่เเรภเลย
So...
ย์งไงครูก็
Nice to meet you all.
ขอฝาภเนื้อฝาภดืวทุภคนตํวยนะ
If you have any problems
เเสํวก็โครมีปัญหาเริ่อง
about school, friends,
ภารเรึยนนะครึบ เริ่อง เพี่ อน
or love,
เริ่องความรึภ
you can talk to me.
ปรึภษาเลยนะ
I'm not just your teacher but also a friend.
อย่าคิดวําเปิ้นครูเเสํวจะเซําถีงยาภ
I'm also part of the alumni of this school.
เพราะจริงๆ ครูก็เปิ้นศิษยใก่าที่นี่เหมีอนก๊น
So I'm practically your upperclassman.
ก็เปิ้นรุ่นพี่พวภเรานื่เเหละ
[students chatting]
[น็ภเรึยนพุดคุย]
[teacher yelling] Why are you being irresponsible?
[ครูผุ้หญิง] มานื่เลย ขี้นมอลิ่ไตํก็เอาเลยนะ
I must keep an eye on you.
เผลอไม่ไตํเลย
Come in! Come in!
นื่ๆ เซําไปเลยๆ
[sighs]
[ถอนหายใจ]
[female teacher] Mr. Phop.
[ควู๊ผุ้หญิง] ควู๊ภพ
Please keep an eye on Liu.
ย์ยหลิวเนี่ย ตัองคอยตูมันใหัดีนะ
She's been rowdy since grade 9.
มันเภ เรมาดั้ง เเตํม อลามละ
She always hangs out with grade 12 kids.
เผลอไม่ไตํเลยอะ ซอบไปสุมหืวก๊บพวภมอหภ
Hey! Greet your teacher!
เอัา ย์งไม่ลวีลดืคุณครูเขาอีภ
[imperceptible]
ครีบ
Oh!
เออ
As a teacher,
เปิ้นครูอะ
you must do the roll-call.
ตัองคอยเซ็ภซึ่อน็ภเรึยนก่อนลอนตัวยนะ
What is your name again?
เธ อซึ่อ อะไรนะ
[students giggling]
[น็ภเรึยนหืวเราะเบาๆ]
You are their teacher,
เธอเปิ้นครู
not their friend or their upperclassman.
ไม่โซ่เปิ้นเพี่อน เปิ้นรุ่นพี่เต็ภพวภนี๊นนะ
So behave like one.
เพราะฉะนี๊นวางดืวใหัถูภ
You must be firm.
มีอะไรก็จ์ดภารใหัเต็ดขาด
If they're not afraid of you,
ถัามันไม่ ภลืว เรา
you cannot control them.
เราก็จะปภครองมันไม่ไตั
And if you can't take care of them,
เเสํว ถัา เราตู เเลมันไม่ไตํ
then you won't pass the performance evaluation.
เธอก็จะไม่ ผ่านภารประเมีน
You won't become a full-time teacher here.
จะไม่ไตัรึบภารบรรจุใหัเปิ้นครูที่นื่
Understand?
เซําโจไหม
Yes.
ครีบ
Anyway, take good care of Natcha.
ไปควบคุมตูเเลย์ยณ์ฐฑใหัดืก็เเสํวก๊น
Prove to me that you are ready to be a teacher.
เเลดงใหัเหึนหน่อย
Okay.
ครีบ
[women chatting]
[ผุ้หญิงพุดคุย]
[man] Phop.
[ผุ้ฑย] เออภพ
How's the school?
วีนนื้มึงไปโรงเรึยนมาเปิ้นย์งไงมั่งอะ
[Phop] It's good. It changed a lot.
[ภพ] ก็ดืนะเฮืย เปลิ่ยนไปเยอะเลย
Oh, right. Do you remember Mrs. Watchani?
เออ เฮีย ครูรึซนีอะ
-Yes, I do. -She's my boss.
-เออ -เปิ้นหืวหน้า
[Phop's brother] Oh, really?
[เฮี่ย] เฮัย จริงอะ
If you can't stand working with her,
ถัามึงทนทํางานก๊บมันไม่ไหวนะ
come work with me.
มาทําก๊บเฮืยก็ไตํ
Wait!
เฮัย เฮืย
Do you really want to do that?
นื่มึงจะฑนมันมาทําก๊บมึงจริงๆ เหรอ
He will ruin your business.
เติ่ยวมันทํามึงเจ๋งนะ
His business in Bangkok failed.
นื่ไม่โซ่เพราะธุรกึจที่ภรุงเทพฯ มันเจ๋งเหรอ
That's why he came here.
มันถีงภล์บมาบ๋านเนื่ย
But really,
เเตํกุพุดจริงนะเวัย ภพ
are you okay with being a teacher?
มึงจะท่าไหวเหรอวะเปิ้นครูเนี่ย
Of course.
ไหวดิเฮืย
Not all kids are rowdy.
ก็เเค่เต็ภมันอาจจะเภเรบ๋าง
[Phop's brother 2] I didn't mean that.
[เฮี่ย] มันไม่โซ่ทํางานไม่ไหวเเบบนี๊น
I mean, the salary.
ไอัเงืนเดือนอะ
Is it enough?
มึงจะไหวเหรอวะ
Now you're getting a trainee's rate, right?
ตอนนื้มึงรึบเรตครูฝืภลอนไม่ใซ่เหรอ
Have they told you when you will be full-time?
เเสํวนื่เขาบอภมึงไหมวําเขาจะบรรจุมึงเมี่อไหร
I have no idea.
-ย์งไม่รู้เลยเฮืย -น็นไง
What about the family's money that you borrowed?
เเสํวเงืนภงลีที่มึงกู้ไปซึอบ๋านในอําเภออีภ
When will you be able to repay?
มึงจะใซํคืนหมดเมี่อไหรหนี๊อะ
Come on.
เเหม เฮืย
We both work so we can repay it in no time.
ฑยก๊นทํางานลองคน เเปืบเดืยวเติ่ยวก็หมด
Right?
โซ่ปะภพ
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[knock on door]
[เคาะประตู]
May I come in, teacher?
ขออนุญาตเซําหัองค่ะคุณครู
I was wondering where you were.
เเหม น็ภวําหายไปไหน
Looking at old photos?
มาหลบตูรูปเก่าๆ นี่เองอะ
-Yeah. -Here.
-อือ -อะ
Drink it.
ส์ภจอภ
For old times.
เพี่อความหลืง
Just a little bit, okay?
นิด เดื ยวนะ
Geez!
-อือ -[เลียงหายใจออภหลืงดิ่มเหสํา]
Let me see.
ไหนตูซิ
Wow.
โห
Cute smile.
ยี้มน่ารึภจีง
A friend.
เพี่ อน
Close friends? There're lots of his photos.
สนิท เหรอเหึนมีรูปเยอะเลย
We were.
ก็สนึทอยู่
Where is he? I've never met him.
เขาหายไปไหนเเสํวอะ ไม่ เหึนเคยพามาใหัรู้จีภ เลย
Is he from around here?
คนเเถวนี๊เหรอ
Not anymore.
ไม่ไตํอยู่เเถวนื้เเสํว
Let's go!
ไป
[Phop] Natthakit.
[ภพ] ณัฐกึจ
Natcha.
ณัฐฑ
[hip-hop instrumental music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงเเนวฮิปฮอป]
Look at that!
เปิ้นไงๆ
[talking indistinctly]
-[ดนตรึฮิปฮอป]
[girl] Hey! What is it?
[ผุ้หญิง] เฮัยอะไรวะ
Fuck! Teacher!
เฮัย ไอัเหี้ย ครูมา
-[gripping instrumental music playing] -Wait!
-[ดนตรึน่าติ่นเตัน] -เร็วดิ เร็ว
Hey! Wait!
เฮัย นี่ เติ่ยว
Wait!
เติ่ยว
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึน่าภลืว]
[clanging]
[ลิ่งของภระทบก๊น]
[footsteps approaching]
[ดนตรึน่าภลืว]
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึตึงเครึยด]
-[shouts] -[screams]
-[ตภโจภล์ว] -[อุทาน]
Hey!
เฮัย นื่
[exciting music playing]
-[ดนตรึติ่นเตัน] -[ภพ] นี
Hey, you! Stop!
เฮัย คนนี๊น ครูบอภใหัหยด
Stop!
หยุด
[exclaiming]
[ตะโภน]
Hey!
เฮัย
Stop!
หยุด
[breathing heavily]
[หายใจห อบ]
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[all laughing]
[ทุภคนหืว เราะ]
Here, wear it.
อะ ใลํไวั
People can see through your shirt.
ซุด เธ อมันโปืไป
Ew! Whose jacket is this?
ไม่เอาอะ ซุดโครเนี่ย
It's mine.
เสี้อครูเนี่ย เเหละ
Wear it. Wearing a wet shirt isn't good. Here.
โลํเอาไวั เติ่ยวคนจะมองไม่ดื เอา
And this is good?
ออ เเสํวนื่คือดืเหรอ
What's wrong with it? Here.
ทําไมอะ อะ
I don't want it. You wear it.
ไม่ เอา ครูเก็บไปโลํเองเหอะ
So lame.
ซุดอะไร ไม่จ๋าบเลย
What are you talking about?
จัาบเจิ้บอะไรก๊น
Wear it now!
รึบโลํเซําไป เลย
Look how wet and dirty you are!
เเตํงดืวอะไรก็ไม่รู้ น่าเภลียด
Can she make the first class in time?
ตกลง เซํา เรึยนคาบ เเรภทํนไหม
Yes, if she hurries.
ย์งทํนนะคร้บ ถัารึบไป
Then go! What are you waiting for?
ทืนก็รึบไปสิ่ จะรออะไรละ
Yes, ma'am.
ครีบ
Phop!
อัาว ภพ
Where are you going?
เเสํว เธอจะไปไหน
Let her go to class.
ก็ใหัณัฐฑ เขา เซํา เรึยนสิ่
You're the teacher.
เธอ เปิ้นครูนะ
[chuckles nervously]
[หืวเราะเบาฯ]
I forgot.
ผมลีมครึบ
I hope there will be a better solution.
หวีงวําจะมึวิธีที่ดืภวํานื้นะ
For next time.
ครั้งต่อไป
Yes.
ครีบ
[birds chirping]
[นภร้อง]
[comical instrumental music plays]
[ดนตรึลดใล]
What are you doing here?
ครูมาทําอะไรที่นี่อะ
Your house is on the way, so I thought I'd pick you up.
พอดืเปิ้นทางฝานครูก็เลยจะมารึบเธอไปโรงเรึยน
It's okay. I can go by myself.
ไม่ตํอง หนูไปเองไตํ
Actually, I didn't want to do this.
จริงๆ ครูก็ไม่อยาภมาตามเธอหรอภ
But Mrs. Ratchani told me to take you to school.
ถัาครูรึซนีไม่ไตํสี่งวําตํองพาเธอไปเรึยนใหัไตัอะ
She's so fucking annoying.
อีรึซนีจะเอาอะไรก๊บกุน็ภหนาวะ
Come on. I'll give you a ride.
เอาน่า เดิ่ยวครูไปลํงเอง
No. I can go by myself.
ไม่เอาอะ หนูจะไปเอง
No, you can't.
ไม่ไตํ
Yes, I can.
ไดั
[comical instrumental music plays]
[ดนตรึตลภๆ]
Why do you stay at the dorm?
ทําไมมาอยู่หออะ
I'm not from here.
ก็ไม่โซ่คนที่นี่
Where are you from?
เเสํวเปิ้นคนที่ไหนอะ
Chiang Rai.
เชียงราย
Not afraid of living alone?
เเสํวอยู่คนเดืยวไม่ภล์ว
There's nothing to be afraid of.
ไม่มีอะไรใหัภล์วหรอภ
I'm not going to stay here long.
เเสํวยํงไงก็จะไม่ไตัอยู่ที่นื่นานอยู่เเสํว
Where are you going to stay?
เเสํวจะไปอยู่ไหน
Anywhere but here.
ที่ไหนก็ไตํที่ไม่ใซ่ที่นี่อะ
I don't belong here.
ที่นื่มันไม่ใซ่ที่ของหลืวอะ
I think maybe you haven't found any good things here yet.
บางทืครูวําเธออาจจะยํงไม่ เจอ
If Pang Noi was good,
เเสํว ถัามันดื
why did you move to Bangkok in grade 12?
ทําไมตอนมอหภครูถีงยัายไปอยู่ภรุงเทพฯ ละ
Wait!
เติ่ยว
How did you know that?
รู้เริ่องครูไตํไง
You're new.
ครูมาใหม่
Everyone talks about you.
โครๆ ก็เมาตธัปะ
[chuckles]
[หืวเราะเบาฯ]
Oh, right.
เออ ก็จริงอะ
My friend and I thought the same as you do now.
ตอนเต็ภๆ ครูก๊บเพี่อนก็ซอบคิดเเบบเธอเนี่ยละ
Right?
ใซ่ปะ
Pang Noi is boring.
เมีองปางน้อยมันไม่มีอะไรอะ
This town is too small.
ผุ้คนก็คืบเเคบ
Everyone knows everyone.
ทําอะไรก็รู้ถีงก๊นหมด
You said you want to leave.
เเสํวที่วําอยาภไปอะ
Where do you want to go?
ไปที่ไหน
Bangkok, Chiang Mai...
กรุงเทพฯ เซึยงใหม่
Anywhere but Pang Noi.
ที่ไหนก็ไตํที่ไม่ใซ่ที่นี่อะ
I think...
ครูวําเนื่ย
you should wait until after you graduate.
เธอเรึยนโหัจบกอนดืกวําไหม
No way!
โห ครู
Are you serious?
ซ็เรึยลปะเนี่ย
I will graduate in three years.
กวําหนูจะเรึยนจบอีกดั้งลามปิ
By that time I'll be insane.
หนูเปิ้นบัาตายกอนพอดื
What did you say?
เมี่อกี้พูดวําไงนะ
I'm in grade 10.
ก็ตอนนื้หนูอยู่มอลิ่
I will graduate in three years.
กวําหนูจะเรึยนจบมันก็อืกลามปิ
Not that.
ไม่ฯ
The other word.
อืกคําน็งอะ
-"Serious"? -Yeah.
-ซ็เรึยลอะนะ -อือ
Why?
ทําไม อะ
[cell phone vibrating]
[โทรคืพทฑ์สี่น]
Hello, Top.
ฮี้ลโหล พี่ท็อป
Yeah, Mr. Phop is giving me a ride to school.
เออ ครูมารึบไปลํงที่โรงเรึยนอะ
Since I got in,
ก็ดั้งเเต่ขี้นรถมา
he just keeps talking.
ครูก็ฑนคุยไม่หยดเลยอะ
Okay. See you at school.
เออ เติ่ยว เจอกืนที่โรง เรียน
Bye.
บาย
Top from grade 12?
ท็อปมอหกอะนะ
Yes.
อือฮี่
Boyfriend?
เเฟน
Sir...
ครุ
It's none of your business.
ไม่ยุ่งดิ
[chuckles]
[หืวเราะเบาฯ]
Okay.
โอ เค
I will go to class when the bell rings.
เติ่ยวถีงเวลาเเสํวหนูไปเซําเรึยนเองค่ะ
Good morning!
ลวีลดีคร้บ
[speaking softly]
[พูดคุยเบาๆ]
"Serious"?
ซีเรียส
[crickets chirping]
[จี๋งหรึดร้อง]
[sighs]
[ถอนหายใจ]
[Phop] Watthana.
[ภพ] วัฒนา
-Kopkul. -Here.
-ก อบกุล -ครึบ
Natcha.
ณัฐฑ
Here.
หนูอยู่นี่
Why did you change seats?
ทําไม เธอเปลิ่ยนที่นื่งละ
There're scratches on that table. It's difficult to write.
โต๊ะดืวนี๊นมันเปิ้นรอย เขืยนหน็งลีอลําบาก
[sighs]
[ถอนหายใจ]
I think every table has scratches.
เเตํครูวําทุกโต๊ะก็มีรอยเหมีอนก๊นนะ
[Liu] I just don't like that table.
[หลืว] เเต่หนูไม่ซอบโต๊ะดืวนี๊นอะ
It feels strange.
นั่งเเสํวมันรู้สึกไม่ค่อยดื
It's okay that I sit here, right?
ครูไม่ชีเรึยลใซ่ไหมถัาหนูขอยัาย
Yeah.
ไม่ชีเรึยล
Sit wherever you want.
นั่งไหนก็ไตํ เลย
Thank you, sir.
ขอบคุณค่ะ
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
Hello.
ลวีลดีคร้บ
All right, everyone.
อะ ทุกคน
Turn to page 57.
เปิดหน้า 57 ครีบ
We'll continue from last time.
ต่อจากคาบที่ เเสํว เล ยนะ
There must be one more activity,
มันยํงตัองมีกึจกรรมอะไรอืกอยางน็ง
so we can evaluate you.
มันถีงจะครบผลการประเมีน
So...
อัอ เเสํว...
What do I have to do?
ตัองทําย์งไงละคร้บ
You must take the students
เธอก็ตํองพาเต็กเนี่ย
to attend any academic activity.
ไปทํากึจกรรมทางวิฑการอะไรก็ไตํ
Like a competition or anything that shows your potential.
ส์กอยางน็งอะ จะไปประกวด ประซํนอะไรก็ไดไหัมันไตัผลงานมา
But...
เเต่...
in the rest of the evaluation, you did very well.
เก ณฑฑ์การประเมึนอี่นๆ
Especially about Natcha.
โดยเฉพาะเริ่องของการตูเเลยํยณัฐฑเนื่ย
[Ratchani] Every teacher said that
[รึซนี] ครูทุกคนเขาบอกวํา
her behavior and grades are infinitely better.
ทั้งพฤตืกรรมเเละการเรึยนดืขี้นอยางไม่น่าเซึ่อ
You are the only one
มีเธอคนเดืยวนะ
who can take care of her.
ที่ตูเเลยํยณัฐฑไตํ
Right.
ครีบ
Now you should figure out
ถัางั้นเธอก็ไปพยายามหน่อยเเสํวก๊น
that academic activity.
เริ่อง ผลงานทางกึจกรรม อะ
[Top] You rarely hang out with us anymore.
[ผุ้ฑย] หล์งๆ มาเนี่ย
Also, the grilled sausage I bought for you,
เเสํวก็ เนื่ย
you don't even eat it.
หลืวยํงไม่ไตํกึนอีกนะ
I told you many times that whenever you buy it,
ก็หลืวบอกดั้งกิ่ครื้งเเสํว
put a vegetable in it, too.
ใหั เอา ผืกในเซเวํนมาตํวย
-Which one? -Lettuce.
-ผืกอะไรหลืว -มันมีผืกลล์ด
They serve it with sausages.
ที่เขาโหัดืกโลํก๊บไลักรอกอะ
They don't have that at 7-Eleven anymore.
ในเซเวํนอะ
-Are you sure? -[Liu] I think
-มั่วปะเนื่ย -[หลืว] พึท็อปอะ
you just don't remember what I said.
ไม่จํามากกวํา มาหาวําหลืวมั่ว
[Top] You're using this as an excuse not to hang out with us, right?
[ท็อป] นื่คือเอาผืกมาอัาง
It's not an excuse. I told you I want to study!
ไม่ไตํอัางเวัย ก็บอกดั้งเเตํเเรกเเสํวไงวําอยากอานหน็งลีอ
[Top] They don't have it.
[รึซนี] ก็มันไม่มีอะ
[Phop] Hey! Stop arguing!
[ภพ] เถียงอะไรก๊น พอเเสํว
Hello.
-หวีดดืคร้บ
Natcha.
เออ ณัฐฑ
I want to talk to you.
ครูมีเริ่องคุยตํวย
-Meet me in the teacher's lounge. -You can talk here.
-ตามไปหัองพักครู... -คุยตรงนีก็ไตํนะคร้บครู
Okay.
ไตํสิ่
I want to know if you'd be interested
ครูจะมาถามวําเธอลนใจจะ
in participating in a science quiz in Chiang Mai.
ไป เเซ่งตอบปืญหาวิทยาฒลตรัที่ เซึยงโหม่ไหม
Me?
หนูเนื่ยนะคะ
Yes.
ใซ่
Your grades are very good.
คะเเนนเธอ เซํา เก ณฑฑ์อยู่นะ
Do you want to go?
อยากไปเซียงใหม่ไหมละ
[pleasant music playing]
[ดนตรึลบายๆ]
Have you ever been to downtown Chiang Mai?
เคยมาดืวเมีองเซียงใหม่มากอนปะ
No, ma'am.
ไม่เคยนะคะ
-If I'm not mistaken. -Hmm?
-ถัาจําไม่ ผิด -หือ
"Mistaken"?
มีจําไม่ผิดตํวย
Well, it feels familiar.
อือ มันคลีบคสํายคล์บคลาอะค่ะ
Thank you.
ขอบคุณครึบ
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[engine accelerating]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[boy 1] What are examples of longitudinal waves?
[ฝุ่ฑย] คลิ่นตามยาวมีอะไรบัาง
-[boy 2] Sound waves. -[girl] Spring wave.
-[ผู้ฑย] คลิ่นเสิ่ยง -[ผุ้หญิง] คลีนโนลปริง
[Phop] Liu.
[ภพ] หลิว
Liu!
หลิว
Yes?
คะ
Daydreaming? Why don't you answer your friend?
คิดอะไรอยู่ ทําไม เธอไม่ตอบคําถามเพี่อน
What was the question?
ถามวําอะไรนะ
I asked,
กุถามวํา
"What are examples of longitudinal waves?"
คลิ่นตามยาวอะมึอะไรบ๋าง
[knock on door]
[เคาะประตู]
-Hey! -Give me the car keys.
-อัาว -ขอกุญเเจรถหน่อยสิ่
I'm going out with my friends.
จะออกไปเที่ยวก๊บเพี่อน
-Drive safely. -Okay.
-ซํบรถดืๆ นะ -อือ
Don't wait up! I'll be late.
ไม่ตํองอยู่รอนะ กล์บดืก
[chuckles softly]
[หื ว เรา อื]
-[kisses] -Good night.
-[บู๊บ] -กู๊ดไนตฑ์
[Phop] Let's continue!
[ภพ] อะต่อ
Okay.
โอ เค
What is an SI base unit?
หน่วยเอลไออะมีอะไรบ๋าง
Are you all right?
เปิ้นอะไรหรึอเปลาหลืว
Go get some rest.
ไป พักฝอน
I don't know, sir.
มันเปิ้นอะไรก็ไม่รู้อะครู
I can't concentrate.
รู้สึกไม่มีลมาธิเเปลกๆ
Want to get some fresh air?
อยากไปซํางนอกไหมละ
It might help.
เผื่อจะดืขึ้น
But Miss Orn took your car.
เเตํครูเอากุญเเจรถใหัพี่อรไปเเสํวนี่
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[engine revs]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
Here.
อะ
They don't serve lettuce
เติ่ยวนื้ ไลักรอกเซเวํนอะ
with sausage at 7-Eleven.
เขาไม่ เเถม ผัก เเสํวนะ
Really?
อาวเหรอ
Where did you get this then?
เเสํวนื่ครูไปหามาจากไหนอะ
Well, it's not that difficult.
เอาน่า หาไม่ยากหรอก
I bought it from another shop.
เเถวนี๊มีของขาย เย อะเเยะ
Do you come to Chiang Mai often?
ครูมาเซียงโหม่ปอยเหรอ
Not really.
ก็ไม่นะ
When I was young.
มาตอนเต็กๆ อะ
I came here for tutoring school.
ครูก็มาเรึยนพึ เศษ
Really? You had to do that?
อยางครูเนี่ยนะ ตํองเรึยนพึ เศษ
I wasn't smart.
ครูไม่ใซ่คนหืวดือะไรหรอก
I was lucky that my friend helped me.
เเตํครูโซคดีที่เพี่อนครูฑยครูไวั
If he didn't drag me to study back then,
ถัามันไม่ลากครูเซําไปเรึยนพึเศษตอนฑงปิดเทอมนะ
I wouldn't be where I am now.
ครูไม่เปิ้นผุ้เปิ้นคนเเบบนื้หรอก
He must be very important to you.
เพี่อนคนนี๊นตํองลําคืญก๊บครูมากเเน่ๆ
He was.
ลําคืญนะ
He certainly was.
ลําคืญมากเลยละ
Where is he now?
เเสํวตอนนี๊เขาอยู่ที่ไหนเหรอคะ
Somewhere around here.
ก็น่าจะอยู่เเถวนี๊เเหละ
Why don't you go find him?
เเสํวครูไม่ไปหาเขาเหรอ
I don't think he would recognize me.
ครูกลีววําถัาไปตอนนื้ เขาจะจําครูไม่ไตํ
He would if you're important to him.
ถัาลําคืญก็ตัองจําไตํสิ่
Right?
จริงไหม
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
Liu.
หลิว
Can I ask you something?
ครูถามหน่อยลิ
Do you believe in reincarnation?
เธอเซึ่อเริ่องการกลืบฑตืมาเกึดไหม
I'm not sure.
ไม่รู๊ตี
I just think that
หนูก็เเค่คืดวา
our other self might be
บางทืมันอาจจะมี
living in another universe
ดืวเราอีกที่น็ง
or another timeline.
หรึอโนอืกเวลาน็ง
Something like that.
อะไรประมาณนี๊นละมั้งคะ
Why do you ask?
เเต่ครูถามทําไมเนี่ย
You are a science teacher.
ครูเปิ้นครูลอนวิทยาฒลตรันะ
I believe that...
ครูก็ เเค่ เซึ่อวา
the reason that we've met
บางทืการที่เราไตํพบก๊น
and known each other
ไตํมาเจอก๊น
is for something special
มันอาจจะเพี่ ออะไรบางอยาง
or...
หรึอวา
we're destined.
ถูกกําหนดเอาไวัเเสํวอะ
Oh, my God!
เซึ่ย ตายหา
I will surely fail tomorrow.
พรุ่งนื้กุตกรอบเเรกเเน่
[laughing]
[หื ว เรา อื]
All right.
โอ เค
I was just asking.
ครูเเค่ถามเฉยๆ
You remind me of someone I know.
เพราะวา เธ อน่ะทําใหั ครูน็ก ถีงใครบางคน
Sir.
ครุ
Miss Orn is a good person.
พี่อรเขาเปิ้นคนดืนะ
[chuckles softly]
[หื ว เรา อื]
No, I don't like you that way.
ไม่โซ่อยางงั้น ครูไม่ไตํคิดอะไรเเบบนี๊น
[chuckles softly] Me neither.
[หืวเราะเบาๆ] หนูก็ไม่ไตํคิดอะไร
I'm just trying my best as a teacher
ครูก็เเค่ทําหน้าที่ที่ครูไตํร้บมอบหมายใหัดืที่ลุด
and you're my responsibility. That's all.
ก็เเค่นี๊นเอง ก็คือการตูเเลเธอ
Really?
ออเหรอคะ
Yes.
ใซ่
Thank you.
ก็ขอบคุณนะคะ
Me too.
เซ่นก๊น
[slow instrumental music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[announcer speaking] Congratulations to the schools
[ประกาศ] ขอเเลดงความดืใจก๊บทุกโรงเรึยน
that won today.
ที่ไตํร้บรางวีลโนวีนนื้ตํวยนะคร้บ
Please, everyone,
ขอเซึญ
come take a photo together.
น้องๆ ทุกท่านมารวมถ่ายรูปเปิ้นที่ระลิกไตํนะครึบผม
-Please. -[Orn] Why are you crying?
-เซิญคร้บ -[ผุ้หญิง] ทําไมคุณครูตาเเดง
It's okay.
อะไร ไม่เอาน่า
It's no big deal.
เริ่องนีดเดียวเองอะ
Oh, honey.
โถๆ โถ
[Orn] Don't cry.
[อร] ไม่ตัองร้องไหันะ
You can go ahead.
เติ่ยวพวกครูกล์บก๊นไปกอนเลย
I will go back by myself.
เติ่ยวหลิวจะกลืบเองค่ะ
[Orn] But you came with us.
[อร] มาก๊บโรงเรึยน เเสํวกล์บเอง
Would that be okay?
เติ่ยวจะเปิ้นปืญหาหรึอเปลา
I will go home.
หลิวจะกสํบบ๋านจริงๆ ค่ะ
My friend is waiting. See you later.
เพี่อนมารอเเสํว เติ่ยวไปกอนนะคะ
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[rain pattering]
[ฝนตก]
[Phop] Today, Miss Angkhana has a meeting
[ภพ] วีนนื้นะครึบ
and won't be teaching.
ไม่ไตํเซําลอนนะ
She assigned you guys homework.
คาบที่เเสํวเนี่ย คุณครูฝากการบ๋านเอาไวั
Please bring it to me.
โครท่า เลร็จ ก็โหัเอามาลํง
[table screeching]
[เลิยงเอี้ยดอัาด]
[school bell ringing]
[เลิยงกริ่ง]
[students] Thank you, teacher.
[น็กเรึยน] ขอบคุณ
Where is your homework?
เเสํวการบ๋านเธอละ
[cell phone ringing]
[ดนตรึจีงหวะเร็ว]
Hey! Who's calling Liu?
มึง ใครโทรหาอีหลิววะ
Where is she?
วามันไปไหน
[line ringing]
[โทรคืพทฑ์ดืง]
What took you so long? What are you doing?
ทําอะไรอยู่เนี่ย ทําไมถีงรึบลายซัจีง
Who the fuck are you?
เเสํวมึงเปิ้นใคร ไอัส์ตวฑ์
-Can I speak to Liu? -Hey!
-ขอคุยก๊บหลิวหน่อย -เดียว
Answer me!
กุถามวามึงเปิ้นใคร
-Mr. Phop. -Who's calling?
-ครูภพเอง -โครอะ
[firewood crackling]
[ก องไฟ]
[Liu] What is it?
[หลิว] ครูมีอะไรหรึอเปลาคะ
Where are you?
เธออยู่ไหนเนี่ย
I'm on the mountain with my friends.
อยู่บนดอย หนูมาขี้นดอยก๊บเพี่อน
[Phop] You should hurry up
[ภพ] การบ๋านครูอืงคณาเนื่ย
and finish Miss Angkhana's homework.
เธอควรจะรึบท่าลํง รู้ไหม
[Liu] But it's due on Monday.
[หลิว] การบ๋านครูอืงคณามืนลํงวีนจีนทรั
Today is Friday.
นื่เพิ่งวีนศุกรั
Isn't it too soon to call?
ครูจะโทรมาทวงอะไรตอนนื้เนี่ย
Well...
ก็นั่นเเหละ
[Phop] I just want to remind you that it's important, all right?
[ภพ] ครูเเค่โทรมาเตือน คะเเนนดืวนื้มันลําคืญ รู้ไหม
I know.
หนุรู๊
Anything else?
ครูมึอะไรอืกหรึอเปลาคะ
No.
ไม่มีเเสํวละ
I'm going to hang up now.
งั้นหนูกสํบไปหาเพี่อนนะ
[line disconnects]
[วางสาย]
Why did he call?
คุยอะไรก๊น
Nothing.
ไม่ไตํคุยไร
-[Top] I asked you a question. -I told you it's nothing.
-[ท็อป] กุถามวามึงคุยอะไรก๊น หา -[หลิว] ก็บอกวาไม่ไตัคุยอะไรไง
-Don't walk away from me. -Ouch!
-มึงอยามาเดินหนีกุ -โอัย
You're hurting me.
กุเจีบ
I'm sorry.
พี่ขอโทษ
But you've been distant lately.
ฑงนื้อะ หลิวหางไป
Since that fucking Phop arrived.
ดั้งเเตํไอัครูภพนื่นเซํามา
So I...
พี่เลย
I told you already
หลิวก็บอกเเสํวไง
that I don't like him.
วาหลิวไม่ไตํคิดอะไร
What about him?
เเต่มันอะ คิดหรึอเปลา
They say...
คนเขาลิอก๊นไปทึ่ว
that you and him hung out together in Chiang Mai.
วามึงอะ
I wasn't going to say anything.
นื่กุวาจะไม่พูดเเล์วนะ
Did you
มึงอะ
sleep with him?
ไปมี อะไรก๊บมันมา เเสํวใซ่ไหม
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึจริงจีง]
[exclaiming]
[เลิยงตํอยเเละซก]
-You bitch! -Easy, Top!
-อืหลิว -ท็อปเอัย ท็อป โจเยินๆ
[Liu] I didn't sleep with him.
[หลิว] กุไม่ไตํมีอะไรก๊บครู
If you believe what they said,
หรึอมึงจะเซึ่อคนอี่น
then screw you.
ก็ เเสํว เเตํมึง
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึตึงเครึยด]
Let go of me!
มึงปลอยกุ
[engine revs]
[เคริ่องยนตโ
[Phop] Wait!
[ภพ] เติ่ยว
Why are you late?
ทําไม ถีงมาลาย
-I woke up late. -I didn't ask you.
-ผมติ่นลายเองครึบ -ครูไม่ไตํถามเธอ
Don't interrupt!
อยาเเทรก
Have some manners.
มีมารยาทตํวย
So why are you late?
วาไง ทําไมถีงมาลาย
[Liu] I was waiting for him.
[หลิว] รอพี่ท็อปไปรึบที่หอมา
[Phop] Natcha, do 20 sit-ups.
[ภพ] ณัฐฑ เธอลุกนั่ง 20 ทื
Natthakit,
ลํวนณ์ฐกึจ
do 50 push-ups.
วิดพี้น 50 ทื
Everyone, do it!
ทุกคน ปฏิบัติ
You don't have to.
หลิวไม่ตํอง
I will do it for her.
ผมรึบโทษเอง
I'm the reason she's late.
ผมเปิ้นคนไปรึบเขาซั
All right.
ก็ไตํ
Keep doing push-ups until I tell you to stop.
เเตํเธอวิดพี้นไปเริ่อยๆ
And you, go to class.
ลํวนเธอ รึบไปเซําเรึยนไตํเเสํว
It's getting late.
เติ่ยวลายไปมากกวานื้
Go!
ไปลิ
Come on.
เร็ว
One.
หนื่ง
Two.
สอง
Three.
ลาม
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึลิกลืบ]
I've reviewed your lyric translating work.
ครูไตํอานการบ๋านงานเเปลเพลง
Today I'll be picking the best one from this class
เเสํวก็... ครูไตํเลิอกผลงาน
to present to you.
ในวีนนื้นะคะ
It's Natcha's, no. 48.
ณัฐฑ เลขที่ 48 ค่ะ
Where are you? Please come up front.
อยู่ไหนคะ เซึญค่ะ
[clapping]
[ปรบมิ่ยิ]
[in English] Come on. Quickly!
คืมออน ควิกลิ่
[in Thai] Please come.
เซิญค่ะ
Here.
นี่ค่ะ
This song is a classic and has a good theme.
เพลงนื้เปิ้นเพลงที่
How did you know about this song?
ไม่ทราบวาณ์ฐฑไปเอาเพลงนี๊มาจากไหนคะ
Well,
ออ
my dad played this song when I was a kid.
พอหนูฟีง
Okay.
โอ เค
Can you please explain the lyrics to your friends?
งั้นฑยอธิบายเนื้อเพลง
Give her a round of applause.
เพี่อนๆ ปรบมีอโหักําล์งใจหน่อยค่ะ
[clapping]
[ปรบมิ่ยิ]
[enchanting instrumental music playing]
[ดนตรึเพลงซับรรเลง]
Why did you do that?
ครูท่า เเบบนื้ทําไม
What did I do?
ครูท่า อะไร
You shouldn't have done that.
ครูไม่ ควรท่า เเบบนี๊
If you fail this subject,
ถัาเธอตกวิฑนื้
you might have to repeat grade 10.
เธออาจจะขั้ชั้น
And you...
เเสํวดืว เธอ เอง
won't be able to leave this town.
จะไม่ไตํไปจากเมีองนื้ซะทื
But you knew what everyone said about us.
เเต่ครูก็รู้
What if they found out about this?
ถัาเขารู้วาครูทําการบ๋านใหัหนูอีกละ
Who would know?
เเสํวโครจะไปรู้ละ
Did you know
เเสํวครูคิดไหม
that Miss Angkhana told me to read it in class?
วาครูอืงคณาจะโหัหลิวออกไปรายงานหน้าซํน
-What if I couldn't answer? -But she said...
-เเสํวถัาหนูตอบไม่ไตํละ -เเตํครูเขาบอกวา
you did very well.
เธอทําไตํดื
You know every word.
เธอรู้จีกคําเเปลเพลงนื้ทุกคํา
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
What do you want?
ครูตัองการอะไรอะ
My friend translated this song for me.
เพี่อนครูคนน็งเคยเเปลเพลงนื้ใหัครู
It made my life better.
มันทําโหัครูมีฑีตที่ดืขึ้น
But I was the one who...
เเต่ครูกล์บทําใหั เขา
made him face bad things in his life.
เจอเเต่เริ่องเเยๆ ขี้นโนซ๊ต
I want to repay someone...
ครูอยากตอบเเทนใครส์กคน
who is pretty much like him.
ที่ เปิ้นดืว เเทนเขาไตํ
Please stop.
หยดเเค่นื้เถอะครู
I want to be like everyone else.
หนูก็เเค่อยากเปิ้นเหมีอนคนอี่นๆ
[melancholic music playing]
[ดนตรึเศร้าๆ บรรเลง]
[young Phop] No one lives at Dew's house?
[ฝุ่ฑย] บัานไอัดิวไม่มีคนอยู่เเสํวเหรอ
What?
อัาว
Dew passed away a long time ago.
ไอัดิวมันตายไปดั้งนานเเสํวภพ
You didn't know?
นื่มึงไม่รู้เหรอ
It's been almost two years now.
ไอัดิวมันตายไปปิกวาๆ เเสํว
Car accident.
รถซนน่ะ
Hey! It happened the same day you ran away.
เอ วีนเดืยวก๊บที่มึงหนีออกจากบ๋าน
I remember that.
กุจําไตํดี
[chuckles]
[หืวเราะเบาฯ]
[Phop's brother 2] People said that
[ผุ้ฑย] เเสํวเเถวบ๋านเเม่งลิอก๊นวา
he was running away with you.
มันจะหนีตามมึงไป
[both laugh]
[หืวเราะทั้งคู่]
Hey!
เฮัย
Was it true?
หรึอวาจริงวะ ภพ
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
No, it wasn't.
-ไม่จริงหรอก -เออ น็นดิ
[indistinct chatting]
[ฝุ่ฑย] มันอาจจะขี่มอเตอปี่ซคไปซื้อกํวยเติ่ยวใหัเเม่ก็ไตํ
[young Phop] They call it "Pha Dang."
[ภพตอนเต็ก] ที่นี่ เขาเรึยกวาผาเเดง
When I feel down,
เวลาที่เรา
I always come here.
เราก็จะมาที่นี่อยู่ปอยๆ
[birds chirping]
[นกร้อง]
Especially when it's sunny like this,
เเสํวยิ่งเวลาฟ่าเปิดเเบบนื้เนี่ยนะ
it is more beautiful.
มันจะลวยมากเลย
[Dew] It's nice.
[ดิว] ดีเนอะ
You have a beautiful spot that you feel connected with.
ภพมีลถานที่ลวยๆ งามๆ
But I've...
เรา อะ
never had a place like that.
ไม่เคยผูกพันก๊บที่ไหนเลย
Why?
ทําไม
We have to move a lot.
เเม่เรายัายที่ทํางานปอยมั้ง
Because of my mom's job.
งานซําราซการน่ะ
Let's come back here.
ไวัเติ่ยวพามาอีกนะ
Okay.
อืม
Now you are a full-time teacher.
ตอนนื้เปิ้นครูเต็มดืวเเสํวนะ
Yes.
ครีบ
There will be more responsibilities.
เเตํมันก็จะมาพร้อมก๊บความรึบผิดซอบที่มากขึ้น
You know that, right?
เธ อรู้ดืใซ่ไหม
Yes, ma'am.
ทราบครึบ
From now on,
จากนื้ไป
you don't have to take care of Natcha.
เธอก็ไม่ตํองไปตูเเลย๊ยณ์ฐฑเเสํวละ
I assigned other students for you to take care of.
ครูมอบหมายใหัเธอไปตูเเลเต็กน็กเรึยนอีกลุ่มหนี่ง
I think you will do well.
ซึ่งเธอน่าจะทําไตํดื
[man] The rules are not to break.
[ผุ้ฑย] กฎระเบียบไม่ใซ่มีไวัเเหก
Understand? Go!
ใซ่ไหม ไป
Quickly!
อยาซัดิ เผต็จ
Stay still!
ยืนนิ่งๆ
I don't want to cut your ear.
เติ่ยวโดนหู
Easy!
ซั
Stand still!
ยืนนิ่งๆ
I told you to cut your hair.
โหัไปดืดมา
It's a school rule.
เรามีกฎมีระเบียบ
Please cut your hair short.
นะ ไปจ์ดการซะตํวย
[woman] Kamonrat, your nails are too long.
[ผุ้หญิง] เลึบยาวเเสํวนะกมลรึตน์ เธอเนี่ย
This hand too. See?
ซํางนื้ก็ยาว เหึนไหม
Please clip them.
ดืดโหัเรึยบร้อย
You can go. Come here, Duangthip.
ไป มา ดวงหิพยฑ์
Hold on!
เติ่ยว
What the fuck do you want?
นื่มึงมึอะไรก๊บกุปะ
Hey!
เฮัย
Don't be rude.
พูดก๊บครูดีๆ
Just want to tell you to cut your hair.
ครูเเค่จะมาตามเธอไปดืด ผม
My hair...
ผม เนื่ย
grows on my head.
มันงอกบนหืวกุ
It's none of your business.
ไปหน็กหืวพวกมึงเหรอ
It's a school rule.
มันเปิ้นกฎของโรงเรึยน
You're a student.
เธอเปิ้นน็กเรึยน
You should follow the rules.
ตัองทําตามกฎโรงเรึยน
Stupid rule!
กฎงี่ เงา
Why must I follow it?
ทําไมกุตํองทําวะ
Please be polite to me.
พูดก๊บครูดีๆ
To you?
ครูเหรอ
I know the reason
กุรู้นะ ที่มึงมาคอยจีบผิดกุเนื่ย
why you've been on my case.
มึงตํองการอะไร
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึจริงจีง]
Let's go, Top.
ไปเหอะ พี่ท็อป
I'll take you to a barber shop.
ไปดืดผมซํางนอกก็ไตํ เติ่ยวหลิวพาไป
It's none of your business. Fuck off!
เเสํวนื่มึงเกี่ยวอะไรหลิว อยายุ่ง
Hey!
เฮัย
[Liu] Let's go.
[หลิว] ไปเหอะ
-I said fuck off! -Hey!
-บอกวาอยามายุ่ง -เฮัย
[groans]
[ร้องคราง]
Well?
เปิ้นไงอะ
How's that?
เกงน็กเหรอ
[breathing heavily]
[หายใจ เเรง]
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึจริงจีง]
I don't fucking care if you're a teacher.
อยาคิดวาเปิ้นครู
Fight me!
หืนมาต่อยก๊บกุดิ
I really want to know, if a pussy like you
กุอยากจะรู้น็ก เเบบมึง
can fight or not.
สู้คนเปิ้นไหม
[thrilling music playing]
[ดนตรึระทึ ก]
[grunting]
[หายใจ เลิยงดืง] [เลิยงฮี่ดฮี้ดตํอญิ
Want to fight?
เอาโซ่ไหม
Stop! Stop!
หยุดฯ หยุดฯ
Stop! Hey! Stop!
-หยด เฮัย หยุด -ท็อป โอเค ท็อป
Stop!
-ท็อป พอละ -หยุด
[male teacher] You are a teacher.
เปิ้นครูนะคร้บ
Even though he started it, you shouldn't have fought back.
[ภาษาเหนีอ] ถีงเต็กจะเริ่มกอนยํงไง
You could get fired for this.
[ภาษาเหนีอ] เริ่องเเบบนี๊เนี่ย
I disagree.
[ภาษาเหนีอ] พี่ไม่เหึนตํวย
You should know...
ครูก็น่าจะรู้นะ
what kind of student Top is.
วานายท็อปเปิ้นคนย์งไง
There should be more appropriate ways.
เเตํมันก็น่าจะมีวิธีการที่ เหมาะสม กวานื้นะครึบ
[Ratchani] How?
[รึซนี] วิธีอะไร
[speaking dialect] How can you deal with delinquents like him?
[ภาษาเหนีอ] จะเหมาะก๊บเต็กเเบบนี๊
[male teacher] If his parents decide
[ครูฝุ่ฑย] ถัาเกึดผุ้ปกครองเอาเริ่องขี้นมา
to press charges,
ถีงชั้นเเจังความเนี่ย
we're in trouble.
จะทํายํงไงครึบ
[Ratchani] What if he had a weapon?
[รึซนี] เเสํวถัาเต็กมันมีอาวุธละ
Can't a teacher act in self-defense?
ครูไม่มีลิทธิบ้องก๊นดืวเหรอ
[male teacher] It depends on who started the fight.
[ครูฝุ่ฑย] มันก็ตํองมาตูครึบ
Natcha.
ณัฐฑ
Can you answer me now? Who started it?
ตกลงตอบครูไตํย์ง สรุป
[slow music playing]
[ดนตรึบรรเลงซัๆ]
[intense music playing]
[ดนตรึจริงจีง]
[Phop] Today a student got expelled because of me.
[ภพ] วีนนื้ภพทําโหัเต็กคนน็งตัองออกจากโรงเรียน
Actually, I should've been fired.
จริงๆ ภพตัองออกตํวย
But Mrs. Ratchani put...
เเตํวาครูรึซนีเขา เอา
her job on the line for me.
ตําเเหน่งดืวเองประก๊นเอาไวัอะ
Anything else you want to say?
ภพมีอะไรอยากจะระบายอืกไหม
No.
ไม่
You should go to bed.
อรไปนอนเห อะ
I want to be alone.
ภพอยากอยู่คนเดืยว
[Top] Liu.
[หึยิป] หลิว
We have to talk.
มาคุยก๊นกอน
Why did you do that?
มึงทําเเบบนื้ทําไม
Because it's wrong.
ก็มันผิดไง
Shouldn't you be on my side?
เเต่มึงควรเซําซํางกุหริอเปลาวะ
[crying] I don't even understand myself.
[ร้องไหวื กุก็ไม่เซําใจดืวเองเหมีอนก๊น
What if I'm not the Liu that you know?
ถัาซํางในห ลิว
Would you still love me?
พี่ท็อปจะย์งรึกหลิวไหม
Have you ever loved me?
เเสํวหลิวรึกพี่หริอเปลาละ
I wanted to love you.
หลิวก็อยากจะรึกพี่นะ
[slow music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลงซัๆ]
[engine starts]
[เคริองยนตโ
[engine accelerating]
[เรงเคริอง]
[phone beeping]
[เลิยงซํอความเซํา]
Need explanation for this picture. Please come and tell me.
[ดนตริลิกล์บบรรเลง]
[Orn] Where are you going?
[อร] ภพจะไปไหน
Running an errand.
ทําธุระอะ
What errand?
ธุระอะไร
I'm not going to ask you.
อรจะไม่ ถามนะ
But please...
เเตํอรขอไตํไหม
stay with me tonight.
อยู่ก๊บอรคืนนื้ไตํไหม
Have a good day!
ดั้งโจสอนนะภพ
Okay.
ครีบ
[intense music playing]
[ดนตริจริงจีง]
[knock on door]
[เคาะประตู]
[Phop] Liu?
[ภพ] หลิว
[slow music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลงซัๆ]
You know all these songs and actors?
รู้จีกเพลงพวกนื้ เเสํวก็ดาราพวกนื้ตํวยเหรอ
Yes.
รู๊
Some songs are familiar.
บางเพลงก็ดุ้นๆ
Well,
เเสํว
what about these 3D pictures?
ภาพสามมึติ๋พวกนี๊อะ
Can you see what's in them?
ตูออกเหรอ
Sometimes I can see it.
บางทืก็ตูออก
Sometimes I see nothing.
บางทืก็มองไม่เหึนอะไรเลย
This one.
รูปนื้
Shrimp.
กุ๊ง
This.
นื่
Pigeon.
นกพึราบ
This one has a whale.
นื่ปลาวาฬ
You taught me how to look at them.
[ภพ] ดิวสอนใหัภพตูภาพพวกนี๊
Actually, I've always been able to see them.
กูรี้งํๆ
But I pretended I couldn't.
เเตํภพเเกสํงตูไม่ออก
So you'd keep talking to me.
จะไตํมีเริ่องคุยก๊นนานๆ
This one.
ภาพนื้อะ
You wouldn't tell me what was in it.
ดิวไม่ยอมเฉลย
I knew what it was, though.
เเตํภพรู้เเสํวละวามันคือถาพ อะไร
But back then,
เเต่วาตอนนี๊น
I wouldn't dare say.
ภพไม่กสําพูด
It's impossible.
เพราะมันเปิ้นไปไม่ไตํ
We both know that, right?
เรา ก็รู้ก๊นใซ่ไหม
I know that you're still here.
ภพรู้วาดิวย์งอยู่ตรงนื้
We still have unfinished business.
ย์งมีเริองติ๋ดคํางก๊นอืกเยอะเลยอะ
Let me make it up to you.
ที่ภพตัองซดใซํดิว
[captivating instrumental music playing]
[ดนตริเพลงซับรรเลง]
Dew?
เปิ้นดิวใซ่ไหม
Dew.
ดิว
[crying]
[ริ้องไหวุ
[thrilling music playing]
[ดนตริจริงจีง]
You have many views. You pedophile!
คนตูเยอะนะครึบ ไอัคุณครูโรคจืต
Please stop.
-พี่ท็อปหยดไตํเเสํว -เฮัย
This is...
เนื่ย
for making me get expelled.
สาหรึบที่มึงทําใหักุโดนไลออก
And this... is for you!
เเสํวเนี่ย สาหรึบมึง
Liu.
หลิว
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
ครูขอโทษ เธอโอเคหริอเปลา
Go talk to Miss Orn!
ครูริบกล์บไปหาพี่ อรก อน
But you...
เเตํ เธ อ
Go!
ไป
[engine roaring]
[เคริองยนตโ
Is Orn here?
อรอยู่ไหมครึบ
She went outside.
พี่อรออกไปซํางนอก
[intense music playing]
[ดนตริจริงจีง]
[engine accelerating]
[เรงเคริอง]
[automated voice speaking] Sorry, the number you've dialed is not available.
[โทรคืพทโ ขอโทษค่ะ ไม่สามารถตีดตํอ เลขหมายปลายทางไดไนขณะนี
Orn.
ยึว๊
It's not what you think.
มันไม่โซ่อยางที่อรคิดนะ
Stop it!
พอเหอะภพ
There's no point talking about it.
จะมาอธิบายอะไรเอาตอนนี๊อะ มันไม่มีประโยซน์เเสํวนะ
Orn, I'm so sorry.
อร ภพขอโทษนะ
I'm not angry at you.
อรไม่ไดโกรธภพนะ
You've been through a lot.
ซ๊ตภพตํอง เจ อบาด เเผลอะไรมาดั้งมากมาย
I'm not angry at all.
อรไม่โกรธภพหรอก
One day,
ส์กวีนน็ง
if we meet again,
ถัาเราไตํเจอก๊นใหม่
I hope we'll be happier.
อรหวีงวาเราคงมีความสขมากกวานื้นะ
[vehicle approaching]
[เคริองยนตโ
[tires screech]
[เลิยงรถเบรก]
[slow music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลงซัๆ]
Phop.
ภพ
I saw the clip.
ครูเหึนวิดืโอนี๊นเเสํวนะ
Okay.
ครีบ
I remember your friend Dew.
ครูจํานายดิวเพี่อนสนึทของเธอไตํ
You do?
ครูจําไตํเหรอคร้บ
I always...
ครูน่ะ
remember everything about my students.
จํา เริองของลูกศิษยไตํเสม อละ
Especially you and Dew.
เธอก๊บนายดิวอะนะ
Don't let the past
อยาใหับาดเเผลในอดืต
hold you back from growing.
มันมาฉุดรื้งไม่ใหั เรา เติ๋บโตไป เปิ้นญ์หญ่เลยนะ
[melancholy music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลงซัๆ]
[sobbing]
[สะอื้น]
[crying]
[ริ้องไหวุ
[Phop] Are you here, Dew?
[ภพ] อยู่ที่นื่หริอเปลาอะดิว
I have something to tell you.
ภพมีอะไรจะบอกดิว
I'm sorry
ภพขอโทษ
for the bad things that happened.
ก๊บเริองเเยๆ ที่มันเกึดขี้น
It's my fault.
ที่ภพทําใหัดิวตัองเจอมาตลอดเลย
[door opens]
[ประตูเปิ้ด]
I will try...
ภพจะพ ยายามนะดิว
to continue living without feeling any guilt.
พยายามเติ๋บโตไปเเบบไม่รู้ลิก
But if that means I have to forget you,
เเตํถัามันคือการลิมดิว
I don't want to do it.
ภพก็ไม่อยากทําหรอก
Because you are my good memory,
เพราะดิวคือความทรงจําดืๆ
the only memory that I have.
ความทรงจําเดืยว
[sighing sadly]
[ถอนหายใจ]
Why do I have to cry for you?
ทําไมกุตัองมาร้องไหไหัมึงตัวยวะ
[sobbing]
[สะอื้น]
I bought you some grilled sausages.
กุซึอไลักรอกเซเวนมาฝากมึง
With some lettuce, too.
กุซื้อผืกมาใหัมึงตํวย
It's hard to buy lettuce these days.
เติ่ยวนื้ผืกมันหายากกวาเดิมนะเวัย
[sighing sadly]
[ถอนหายใจ]
[crying] So I bought you a lot.
[สะอี้น] กุซื้อมาหลายอืนเลย
Eat as much as you want!
มึงกึนโหัสบาย
[slow music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลงซัๆ]
I have so many things to tell you.
กุมีอะไรอืกหลายอยางที่กุอยากจะบอกมึง
I'll see you soon.
เอาไวัมึงก๊บกุเจอก๊น
[sobbing]
[สะอื้น]
[young Phop] Is it a sky?
ทํองฟีาปะ
[Dew] Why do you think it's a sky?
ทําไม ถีงคิดวาเปิ้นทํองฟีา
Because it's blue.
ก็มันลิฟ่าอะ
This one is a pigeon.
อืนนื้อะ นกพึราบ
[young Phop] I almost got it right.
มันก็เกือบถูกหน็
[Dew] Okay, last one.
งั้นรูปนื้รูปสดทํายนะ
Figure it out.
ตัองตูโหัออกนะ
[Phop] I already knew what it was.
[ภพ] ภพรู้เเสํวละวามันคือภาพอะไร
But back then...
เเต่วาตอนนี๊น
It's impossible. We both know that, right?
มันเปิ้นไปไม่ไตํอะ เราก็รู้ก๊นใซ่ไหม
[stately instrumental music playing]
[ดนตริเพลงซับรรเลง]
Let's come back here.
ไวัจะพามาอีกนะ
Liu! What's wrong?
หลิว เปิ้นอะไร
Can I borrow your bike?
เรายืมรถหน่อยนะ
Hey! Liu!
เฮัย หลิว
[engine starts]
[เคริองยนตโ
Hey! You can ride it?
เฮัย หลิว ซํบเปิ้นเหรอ
Liu!
หลิว
What the hell?
อะไรวะ
[engine accelerating]
[เคริองยนตโ
[stately instrumental music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลง]
[train horn tooting]
[เลิยงกริงรถไฟ]
[tires screech]
[เลิยงรถเบรก]
[crashes]
[รถพลืกิ]
[slow music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลงซัๆ]
[indistinct chatter]
[พูดคุยพึมพํา]
Phop.
ภพ
[stately instrumental music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลง]
[train approaching]
[รถไฟ่]
[young Phop] I wonder what'll happen next.
[ภพ] ซํางหน้าจะเปิ้นย์งไงตํอไปก็ไม่รู้เนาะ
Where have you been?
ดิวไปอยู่ไหนมาเนื่ย
I have no idea.
ไม่รู๊สิ้
It's like a dream.
เหมึอนผืนไปอะ
A long dream.
ผืนไปนานๆ
When I woke up,
เเสํวพอติ่นขี้นมาอีกทือะ
I was someone else.
เราก็กลายเปิ้นคนอี่น
No old memory left.
ที่ไม่มีความทรงจําเดิมเลย
When we were in Chiang Mai, did you remember?
ตอนเซึยงใหม่ ดิวจําไตํหริอย์ง
[Dew] A little bit.
ก็นีดน็งอะ
But you had a wife.
เเตํวาภพ ก็มี เมี ย เเสํว
I don't want to break up your family.
ดิวไม่อยากทําครอบครึวภพเเตกเเยกอะ
So...
เเสํว
What about Top?
ท็อปละ
We both ruined it.
เราทํามันพังทั้งคู่เลยเนาะ
[sighs]
[หายโจออก]
Yeah.
นั่นลิ
Come sit here.
ดิวมานั่งนื่ลิ
[Phop] Soon
[ผุ้ฑย] อีกไม่นาน
I will get older.
ภพก็จะเเกขึ้น
You'll become an adult.
ดิวก็โตขึ้น
You will find someone better than me.
ดิวคงเจอคนที่ตูเเลดิวไตํดืกวาภพ
I don't want to grow up.
ดิวไม่อยากโตขี้นเลย
Me too.
เหมีอนก๊น
♪ At the horizon ♪
มิเเสนไกลอยู่อีกขอบฟ่ามิ
♪ We wish to climb the rainbow ♪
มิเรามี ผืนจะปินปายมิ
♪ Because at the end Our dream will come true ♪
มิเพราะสดปลายจะสมปรารถนามิ
♪ So we made a wish ♪
อืเราจีงอธิษฐานมิ
♪ Waiting for the day ♪
อืเก็บความล์บไวัรอคืนวีนมิ
♪ To reach The end of the rainbow together ♪
มิเมี่อปลายทางรุ้งถีงตํวยก๊นมิ
♪ We do as we promised ♪
มิส์ญญาจะเอยเฉลยที่ขอมายิ
♪ Each day we climb higher and higher ♪
อืเเตํละวีนที่ปินขี้นสูงมิ
♪ Just see your smile And I won't be afraid ♪
มิเพึยงเธอย์งยี้มฉืนไม่เคยหวี่นมิ
♪ When we're about to reach the end ♪
อืเกือบจะเหึนปลายทางที่ผืนมิ
♪ I turn around but you disappear ♪
มิหืนไปมองเเต่เธอกล์บหายไปมิ
[man] Okay. Come up now.
[ผุ้ฑย] โอเค ครึบผม เอาขึ้นเลยครึบผม
Be careful!
ระวีงหน่อยนะครึบ
Here.
เซึญเลยครึบ เซึญเลยๆ
Okay, this way.
โอเค พี่เซิญตํานนื้คร้บ อยู่ตํานนี๊เร็ว
This way. Okay.
ตํานนื้เนอะ มา มาทางนื้ดิ๊
Sir, please spread your legs.
รบกวนพี่ ผุ้ฑยกางขาหน่อยครึบ
[slow music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลงซัๆ]
Down there...
ซํางลางนั่น
isn't the end, right?
จะไม่ใซ่จดจบใซ่ไหม
No, it isn't.
ไม่หรอก
There will be a path.
มันจะมีทางไปตํอเเหละ
[people shouting]
[ผุ้ฑยตะโกน] เฮัย คนตกนิ้า
[woman screaming]
-[ผุ้ฑยตะโกน] คนตกนิ้า -[ผุ้หญิงกริดร้อง]
[water splashing]
[เลิยงตกกระเเทกนิ้า]
[stately instrumental music playing]
[ดนตริติ่นเตันบรรเลง]
[music increases in tempo]
[ดนตริจ์งหวะเร็วขี้น]
[music stops]
[ดนตริหยด]
[music playing]
[ดนตริเลนตํอ]
[slow music playing]
[ดนตริบรรเลงซัๆ]
♪ Before the sky turns bright ♪
อืกอนทํองฟ่าจะสดโสมิ
♪ Before feeling the warmth of sunlight ♪
อืกอนความอบอุ่นของไอเเดดมิ
♪ Before the flowers bloom ♪
อืกอนดอกไมัจะผลิบานมิ
♪ Before having a sweet dream ♪
อืก่ อนความ ฝ้นอืนเเสนหวานมิ
♪ Before the sky is full of stars ♪
มิกอนดวงดาวจะเต็มฟ่ามิ
♪ Before realizing how precious life is ♪
อืก่อนฑีตจะรู้คุณค่ามิ
♪ Before the faith is gone ♪
อืก่ อนลินศรึทธาจากหืวใจมิ
♪ Before I became hopeless ♪
มิกอนที่คนอยางฉืนจะหมดไฟมิ
♪ I've never had anyone in my heart ♪
อืโนใจไม่ เค ยมี ญ์ดมิ
♪ Till your love came ♪
มิจนความรึก เธอ เซํามาอื
♪ And made me see the brightness ♪
มิทําใหัดวงตาฉืนเหึนความสดใสมิ
♪ I've never had anyone beside me ♪
มิซํางกายไม่เคยมี ญ์ดมิ
♪ Till your love motivated me ♪
มิจนความรึก เธอ เมตตามิ
♪ To keep fighting ♪
อืเปิ้นพ ลืงโหัฉืนสู้ตํอไปมิ
♪ In this cruel world ♪
มิบนโลกที่โหดร้า ยมิ
♪ So cruel ♪
อืเหลิอเกึนมิ
♪ I'll give you ♪
อืทั้งวิญญาณเเละหืวใจมิ
♪ My heart and soul ♪
อืโหัเธอครอบครองมิ
♪ I promise ♪
มิทั้งฑีตโหัส์ญญามิ
♪ I will live and fight for you ♪
มิจะอยู่ จะสู้เพี่อเธอมิ
♪ I've never had anyone in my heart ♪
อืโนใจไม่ เค ยมี ญ์ดมิ
♪ Till your love came ♪
มิจนความรึก เธอ เซํามาอื
♪ And made me see the brightness ♪
มิทําใหัดวงตาฉืนเหึนความสดใสมิ
♪ I've never had anyone beside me ♪
มิซํางกายไม่เคยมี ญ์ดมิ
♪ Till your love motivated me ♪
มิจนความรึก เธอ เมตตามิ
♪ To keep fighting ♪
อืเปิ้นพ ลืงโหัฉืนสู้ตํอไปมิ
[music increases in tempo]
[ดนตริจ์งหวะเร็วขี้น]
[music stops]
[ดนตริหยด]